<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Juan Orozco</title>
  <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Juan Orozco</name>
    <uri>https://www.juanorozco.com/</uri>
  </author>
  <icon>https://www.juanorozco.com/images/brand/icon-1-1.png</icon>
  <logo>https://www.juanorozco.com/images/brand/icon-2-1.png</logo>
  <updated>2020-04-05T03:14:01Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.juanorozco.com/feed.atom" hreflang="en-us"/>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.juanorozco.com/" hreflang="en-us"/>
  <entry>
    <title>Notebooks</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2020/01/23/notebooks/</id>
    <updated>2020-01-23T22:05:41Z</updated>
    <published>2020-01-23T22:05:41Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Field Notes make some &lt;strong&gt;amazing&lt;/strong&gt; notebooks. My favorite, to this day, is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://fieldnotesbrand.com/products/shelterwood&#34;&gt;Shelterwood&lt;/a&gt; from the Field Notes quarterly subscription. A pocket sized notebook wrapped in a super thin vineer of cherry wood - just beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, they&#39;re just &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; small for planning and daily use - at least for me. To try to understand why, I experiemented with the opposite side of the spectrum. I started using an extra large size Moleskine cahier to see what my experience was with more real estate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized two things. 1) Turning pages back and forth, searching for things, is a waste of time. &lt;strong&gt;Page turning reduces task momentum.&lt;/strong&gt; I sorta follow the bullet journal framework so I like to see as much of my day and week as possible. And 2, my daily notebook needs to be portable and &amp;quot;deskable&amp;quot; (basically, it needs to be easy to carry and can also comfortably share a desk with my keyboard and mouse and coffee).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/23174006/img_5231-1024x768.jpg?resize=580%2C435&amp;#038;ssl=1&#34; alt=&#34;Evernote Moleskine Notebook&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t have any shortage of notebooks at home and I quickly found an unfinished Evernote Moleskine I&#39;ve had for years. In fact, I started writing in it in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past month, this size has been great. Still wish it was slightly smaller but I think I&#39;m going to try a soft cover next to see if that helps make it more portable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Field Notes are still great notebooks. I find that I still carry them when I&#39;m working in the yard or generally just out and about - it&#39;s really easy to use my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spacepen.com/bullet.aspx&#34;&gt;Spacepen&lt;/a&gt; and take down a few notes. I can then &amp;quot;inbox&amp;quot; my small notebook into my main notebook. But I don&#39;t use it for journaling anymore.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Arena</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/09/15/3190/</id>
    <updated>2019-09-16T03:20:27Z</updated>
    <published>2019-09-16T03:20:27Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not the critic who counts; not the man who points out how the strong man stumbles, or where the doer of deeds could have done them better. The credit belongs to the man who is actually in the arena, whose face is marred by dust and sweat and blood; who strives valiantly; who errs, who comes short again and again, because there is no effort without error and shortcoming; but who does actually strive to do the deeds; who knows great enthusiasms, the great devotions; who spends himself in a worthy cause; who at the best knows in the end the triumph of high achievement, and who at the worst, if he fails, at least fails while daring greatly, so that his place shall never be with those cold and timid souls who neither know victory nor defeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theodore Roosevelt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talk about this with friends and family quite a lot. Especially my kids. My daughter loves art and draws and doodles constantly. I asked her to publish her work once, but she was afraid to be judged harshly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to do the work, to make mistakes, to make poor decisions and then be judged by those who do not know your fight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell my daughter not to take judgment personally, these people aren’t in the arena with her. I don’t put unrealistic expectations on her or push her to do anything that doesn&#39;t fall within her passions, but at the same time, I try to challenge her and everyone’s ability to value their decisions. Bad or good, poor or beneficial - it doesn&#39;t matter because they are decisions we made in the arena. &lt;strong&gt;And they are ours alone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve come to realize that this &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; an ability - one we&#39;re never perfect at and one we need to exercise &lt;em&gt;constantly&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anker USB-C Charger</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/08/05/anker-usb-c-charger/</id>
    <updated>2019-08-06T01:08:07Z</updated>
    <published>2019-08-06T01:08:07Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bought an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anker.com/products/variant/powerport-atom-iii-2-ports/A2322121&#34;&gt;Anker USB-C charger&lt;/a&gt; because I finally got tired of forgetting my one and only USB-C charger at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple 80 watt charger now stays at home with my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anker.com/products/variant/usbc-to-usbc-thunderbolt-30-cable/A8486011&#34;&gt;Anker powerline USB-C cable&lt;/a&gt;, which is actually capable of deliverying the full 80 watts (technically, 100 watts) from the charger, unlike the included Apple cable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always kept the 2 Amp iPad charger in my bag but with the new Anker, I don&#39;t need to. One charger to rule them all. The USB-A port on the Anker can do 15 watts, which ends up being about 3 amps at 5 volts. Not bad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Anker stays in my bag now. It can only do 45 watts to the laptop which &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a little low but all that means is that I&#39;ll be charging a little slower. If I ever have to travel, I&#39;ll probably take the 80 watt with me. Maybe. I really like the size of the Anker charger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than the lower power rating, the only other downside is that I can&#39;t swap out the plug with an extension. Not a deal breaker but some people use that a lot, I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/05210817/img_4399.jpg?w=580&amp;#038;ssl=1&#34; alt=&#34;Charger Ports&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/05210818/img_4398.jpg?w=580&amp;#038;ssl=1&#34; alt=&#34;Charger profiles&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Releasing Often</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/07/31/releasing-often/</id>
    <updated>2019-08-01T03:56:28Z</updated>
    <published>2019-08-01T03:56:28Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A couple of months back, my wife was working on updating our fence. Specifically, she was improving the gates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had two gates. On the west side of the house, we had a small gate – mostly for people but wide enough for a mower. On the east side, we had a more massive vehicle entry. When we first built the fence about ten years ago, we had no idea what we were doing. We worked with what we had, and, in the end, we built a solid, working fence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The large gate was held closed with four screws. (I kinda wish I had taken photos of all this…) The small gate had a latch, but the gate was a tidge too beefy and would rub when it closed, making it difficult to latch the lock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put simply, it sucked. It wasn&#39;t the best experience, but the fence and gates served us well for ten years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fence: Mark II&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new gates are a considerable improvement. In fact, there are now &lt;strong&gt;three&lt;/strong&gt; gates. Two small gates, one on each side, and one large gate that actually swings open without having to unscrew it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with slightly more knowledge than ten years ago, we began the rebuild with diligence. It also helps that the internet is a more vibrant place in terms of sharing knowledge compared to last decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing my wife built was the new, small gate. The kick-off for the project was drilling into cement so the latch post could go up. Apparently, drilling into cement was fun - I didn&#39;t participate in much of the build if any. (I just fund this operation. She gets to do all the fun stuff! 😆 ). After the first gate went up, a section of fencing went up. The next day, another part of fencing went up then another and another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, she made it to the large gate. The large gate we thought about and researched for a bit. It was a swinging gate, so we knew it was going to be heavy and would need additional support. The large gate went up, and she continued to move along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was when I noticed what she was doing. &lt;strong&gt;She was releasing something every day.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Release_early,_release_often&#34;&gt;common strategy in software development&lt;/a&gt;. Yet, it was interesting seeing my wife commit to deliverables for that day and work towards her goals. Some days she would hit her targets, while other days, challenges would force her to revisit her commitments. Either way, she tried to “release” something every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the two of us - her building and me helping as needed, mostly to bounce ideas off of - we were able to make changes daily. Sometimes more frequent than that! Compared to software, a fence is straightforward, so two people working on something of this complexity makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Perils of Releasing Often&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Releasing often&amp;quot; can be dangerous. It requires discipline from the team at every level - from users to managers and beyond. These days, the term &amp;quot;releasing often&amp;quot; seems to come more often from business managers than engineering managers and serves as a buzzword to convince stakeholders that the team can, and will, deliver value incredibly fast. That isn&#39;t fair to the people in the trenches. Often because engineering teams are understaffed and middle managers are forced to overpromise on deliverables to director level folk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One could argue that the above is all just a communication break down. I agree with that, but there&#39;s more to the story than only communication. I think there&#39;s a systemic problem brewing. But that&#39;s a post for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our fence was built by people that had the autonomy to decide timelines, research solutions, and choose the build strategies. Along with more ethical decision making in engineering, I hope to see more independence given to engineering teams. Which should result in more fair representation at the decision table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not saying work should be easy, we &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be challenged! But there is no need to sacrifice quality and humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our fence isn&#39;t software. But it is &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; hard to CMD&#43;Z a cemented post. Yet, we got much more beautiful &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; usable fence this time around.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I’ve been a parent too long…</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/07/10/ive-been-a-parent-too-long/</id>
    <updated>2019-07-11T00:08:50Z</updated>
    <published>2019-07-11T00:08:50Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;How did I get here? Discussing Paw Patrol lore and fan theories. Le sigh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/10200645/image.png?w=580&amp;#038;ssl=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-3146&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/10200645/image.png?w=580&amp;#038;ssl=1 366w, https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/10200645/image.png?w=580&amp;#038;ssl=1 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 366px) 100vw, 366px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Puppies…</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/05/22/puppies/</id>
    <updated>2019-05-23T00:15:40Z</updated>
    <published>2019-05-23T00:15:40Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last year, we found out that Timber, our family dog, had cancer. We decided to give him a good death and after he was gone, the family had a hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what does my bleeding heart of a wife do? She gets *two* puppies to fill that hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&#39;ve been great. We&#39;ve all learned a lot about ourselves and about caring for animals. Timber came to us a trained (ish) adult. So, two puppies were a huge &lt;g class=&#34;gr_ gr\_180 gr-alert gr\_gramm gr\_inline\_cards gr\_run\_anim Grammar only-ins replaceWithoutSep&#34; id=&#34;180&#34; data-gr-id=&#34;180&#34;&gt;shift&lt;/g&gt; of our day-to-day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One such shift is learning not to leave important things in the yard unattended for too long.&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/22164503/IMG_3548.jpg?w=580&amp;#038;ssl=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-3140&#34; srcset=&#34;https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/22164503/IMG_3548.jpg 3420w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/22164503/IMG_3548.jpg 300w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/22164503/IMG_3548.jpg 768w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/22164503/IMG_3548.jpg 1024w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/22164503/IMG_3548.jpg 1568w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/22164503/IMG_3548.jpg 1160w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/22164503/IMG_3548.jpg 1740w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;There is a wiring harness that comes out of the steel tubing for the lights. The dogs chewed through the harness at the worst possible location, right as the wires come out of the metal hole. Now I have to fix the wiring harness on my utility trailer before I can use it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dogs are great. Raising children has been a difficult but rewarding journey. Raising puppies is similar. I would only recommend either if you truly understand that there will be heartache and anger. There will be twice as much love and laughter, too, though.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>2018 Books</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/03/16/2018-books/</id>
    <updated>2019-03-16T04:21:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-03-16T04:21:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of my &amp;quot;intentions&amp;quot; last year was to read more. Unfortunately, I didn&#39;t read nearly as much as I wanted to. &lt;em&gt;Technically&lt;/em&gt; I didn&#39;t read much at all, I &lt;em&gt;listened&lt;/em&gt;. Regardless, I am pretty happy that I set up the behavior to enjoy books this last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to read a lot more as a kid. These days, I don&#39;t have the time or don&#39;t want to sit idly for so long. I want to change that. Again, for now, I&#39;m just happy that I&#39;m giving my brain some different kind of creative food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Power of Habit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Handmaid&#39;s Tale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Confidential (RIP Tony)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ready Player One (again)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outside the Wire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Howl&#39;s Moving Castle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Children of the Mind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artemis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hyperion (I think I finished this in December but can&#39;t remember...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperion is by far the best thing I &amp;quot;read&amp;quot; last year. Handmaid&#39;s Tale is &lt;strong&gt;bleak&lt;/strong&gt; and disturbing as hell but kinda mind-blowing at the same time (I can see some of that stuff actually happening). Kitchen Confidential was important to me because I so love Anthony Burdain&#39;s views towards life. Oddly enough, I learned more about leadership from his book than I thought I would.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What is introspection</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/03/08/what-is-introspection/</id>
    <updated>2019-03-09T04:23:38Z</updated>
    <published>2019-03-09T04:23:38Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;How do you learn from mistakes? How do you see challenges? How do you take critique?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been wondering and theorizing about my own ability to self-analyze. I assume most people feel the same way towards self and others, that we all want success and happiness. Whatever that means to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, what I see, sometimes, is a sort of slow self-destruction through stagnation or through arrogance. Do we see failure as being easier than change? Change &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; hard, but remaining static is deadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been there. I have failed HARD. I took a step back, looked at how my actions got me there and thought critically what I could have done differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I did mostly everything right with the knowledge I had at the time. Sometimes I could have sought more knowledge. Sometimes, I could have been more proactive. Regardless, in every case, there were opportunities for growth; for change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The really big failures caused the most stress and the most change. But also resulted in the most opportunities for happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not offering an answer here, just the question: &lt;strong&gt;Is change really worth giving up being happier?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Quick Movie Reviews – Annihilation and Automata</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/02/27/quick-movie-reviews-annihilation-and-automata/</id>
    <updated>2019-02-28T03:36:50Z</updated>
    <published>2019-02-28T03:36:50Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been a HUGE Natalie Portman fan since &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110413/&#34;&gt;Leon&lt;/a&gt; (and a MEGA Gary Oldman fan for equally as long). I don&#39;t really have a problem with the Star Wars prequels but her participation in the Thor movies was totally punching below her weight. Still, if she had fun that&#39;s all that matters. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mars_Attacks!&#34;&gt;Mars Attacks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/V_for_Vendetta_(film)&#34;&gt;V for Vandetta&lt;/a&gt; are more of my favorites. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Swan_(film)&#34;&gt;Black Swan&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Other_Boleyn_Girl_(2008_film)&#34;&gt;The Other Boleyn Girl&lt;/a&gt;, great performances of hers but not really my thing as far as movies go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched Annihilation, finally, after discovering &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Annihilation-Natalie-Portman/dp/B079Z18D2Z/&#34;&gt;it was on Amazon Prime&lt;/a&gt;. I enjoyed the subtlety, striking images, and depth so so much. I am surprised that Annihilation slipped past my radar when it released - I feel bad not having watched it sooner! The ending blew me away - I sat there and almost rewatched the final scene where she enters the lighthouse. I didn&#39;t because, well, life. Still, that ending is jammed pack with subtlety. It&#39;s beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ending is presented in a subjective manner, it could mean so many things. Ultimately, I just really enjoy philosophical movies like this, movies that show us some analog to life that causes us to question things. I LOVE THAT. I love wondering and pondering. I love different points of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I had time to watch it again. Instead, I took to the internet to find out what other people thought of it. I found discussions about how the movie is about self-destruction, mutations, cancer, corruption, change, death, life...  &lt;strong&gt;I agree&lt;/strong&gt;. With all of it, especially the theme of self-destruction and with change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With respects to people that have been touched by depression, loss, and cancer - I thought this movie touched on these subjects with sensitivity. The film is a good discussion on what happens when we self-destruct but from a point of view of an ecosystem instead of a single mind. I mean, when you break it down, people and planets are both organisms made up of other organisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, so here&#39;s how I rate films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Own a hardcopy. (I love digital copies but I&#39;m getting old so I think I have to say &amp;quot;hardcopy&amp;quot; soon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch it... as soon as you can. Renting is fine but you &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; want to own it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch it... when you can. Wait for streaming services to get it. Or rent it if you like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch it when you have nothing else to watch. It&#39;s entertaining, at least.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignore it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annihilation is definitely a hard &amp;quot;own it&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-cover has-background-dim&#34; style=&#34;background-image:url(https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/27222240/automata.jpeg)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-block-cover-text&#34;&gt;
    Automata
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t remember this movie doing to well. The intro made me wince. I&#39;m a fan of less is more. If you need to explain a lot in the beginning, we&#39;re likely going to have &amp;quot;story telling&amp;quot; issues throughout. The plentiful text was followed up by a decent credit montage that showed a sort of golden age of human ingenuity trending to the downfall of society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back, the montage is basically a high-level view of the movie. The rest of the film is just this one random dude&#39;s moment that allows watchers to relate so they can understand the montage. /shrug&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was &lt;em&gt;OK&lt;/em&gt;. I like Antonio Banderas - Assassins is a guilty pleasure of mine, as corny as Antonio&#39;s acting was in that film. I also really love Desperado (and the El Mariachi trilogy overall - first movie is the best, of course). He was pretty good in this as well. He exercises some range to go from this overworked jaded guy to this freaked out guy to a somewhat inner peace guy. Not award worthy but not horrible either. His final scene is pretty damn good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story telling did, in fact, have issues, though. There were interesting things being discussed but then... meh. Ohhhh!! Super intelligence?! Neat! Wait, no, sorry... just self-awareness. Still cool but we are sold so hard on the &amp;quot;super brain&amp;quot; thing for nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is repeated throughout the movie - plenty of rope-a-doping. There&#39;s talk about the main character betraying his species. Super interesting! Yes, let&#39;s go there. Oh, wait, this just in... Nope, it doesn&#39;t seem like we&#39;re going there after all, sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end we find out that humans suck and we really don&#39;t deserve the chance of life we were given. I mean, fair point but there was nothing driving the story to that point. The only support for this was the typical homicidal henchman antagonist. Ok, there were other characters that supported the &amp;quot;humans deserve extinction&amp;quot; idea but their screen time was brief and their contributions lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember looking forward to this movie but when I saw how poorly it did, I just never looked back. I saw it was on Netflix and decided to finally watch it. That fits perfectly in line with my rating for it: &lt;strong&gt;Watch it when you have nothing else to watch.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, one thing that reallllyyy bugs me? The beginning of the film, Antonio&#39;s character shows a family how safe robots are by trying to drop a knife on his own hand. The robot demonstrates some agility by quickly catching the knife before it can hurt Antonio&#39;s hand. That must have been the latest model robot because the rest of the robots can&#39;t move as fast to literally save their own lives from bullets and such. Ugh! *shakes fist*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go watch Annihilation.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Burn Out</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/02/08/burn-out/</id>
    <updated>2019-02-08T12:34:33Z</updated>
    <published>2019-02-08T12:34:33Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I started watching &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1YzwjfwNeEg&#34;&gt;Casey Neistat&#39;s latest video about YouTubers experiencing burn out&lt;/a&gt;. I eye-rolled at the title but I respect &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jG7dSXcfVqE&#34;&gt;Casey&#39;s views on life&lt;/a&gt;, so I watched it. It took me two sittings because in the beginning he seemed to over-empathize with his peers and I quickly lost interest with the story he told.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chasing notoriety on any medium is not sustainable. We&#39;ve seen so many people crash and burn because of that. Promising careers in, well, whatever - cut short because... well, who knows what they were thinking or what their motivations were at the time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, people like first responders, war fighters, and emergency medical staff face difficult issues daily. Compassion fatigue is a huge one. PTSD, death... those are difficult careers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, who deserves our empathy and time between the two groups? Well, as compassionate and understanding human beings, our answer should be &amp;quot;both&amp;quot;. We should care for *all* our brothers&#39; and sisters&#39; well-being... regardless of chosen career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The questions we *should* be asking are, do you own your life? Do you own your decisions. Do you own the consequences of your decisions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer to these questions are not a prerequisite to deserving compassion. Sometimes, the consequences of our decisions are unforeseen, debilitating and long-lasting. It definitely helps when friends and family respond to someone&#39;s needs, furthermore, it should never prevent them from reaching out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What feels right, though, is that more study is required on burnout. &amp;quot;Burn Out&amp;quot; should be a spectrum, yet also something that requires an official diagnosis. Right now, anyone can say they have burnout without really understanding it, without really understanding that there are people deeply, physically, mentally, and emotionally affected by it. This makes it harder for people with actual burnout to get the help they need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the technology industry, specifically software engineering, there are a growing number of people that are overworked and over-stressed and I want to understand the problem so I can help with solutions. Personally, I&#39;ve felt some effects of burnout, although never to the degree where I can say I have experienced true burnout. Still, I am aware of it; what it can do to you and what it can do to the people around you. As an area of scientific research, I know nothing, but I&#39;m learning more. &lt;a href=&#34;https://pinboard.in/u:guamaso/t:burnout/&#34;&gt;Here&#39;s a collection of articles&lt;/a&gt; that I&#39;ve started to read that might help if you&#39;re looking to learn more, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, be considerate and be understanding. You usually can&#39;t go wrong with that approach. 😉&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Wolf Blood Moon</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/01/22/wolf-blood-moon/</id>
    <updated>2019-01-22T15:33:31Z</updated>
    <published>2019-01-22T15:33:31Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the past ten years, we&#39;ve seen three total lunar eclipses where &#39;round these parts. Every time, though, circumstances prevented us from seeing it - clouds, really effing late hours, etc. This, year, though, we had a clear night and it wasn&#39;t too late in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kiddos were weirded out by how lifeless the moon looked. In fact, it took them a solid moment to actually *find* the moon in the sky. Unfortunately, none of the kids seem to share my love for the wonder of our universe. At best, they find it mildly interesting. They did wake up at midnight just to see the eclipse but they came and went after a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can work with that, though. The fact that they got out of bed... that&#39;s something. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;wp-block-gallery columns-3 is-cropped&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&#34;blocks-gallery-item&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222935/DSC09104.jpg?w=580&amp;#038;ssl=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; data-id=&#34;93&#34; data-link=&#34;https://www.juanorozco.com/?attachment_id=93&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-93&#34; srcset=&#34;https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222935/DSC09104.jpg 5611w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222935/DSC09104.jpg 300w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222935/DSC09104.jpg 768w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222935/DSC09104.jpg 1024w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222935/DSC09104.jpg 1568w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222935/DSC09104.jpg 1160w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222935/DSC09104.jpg 1740w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&#34;blocks-gallery-item&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222943/DSC09077.jpg?w=580&amp;#038;ssl=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; data-id=&#34;94&#34; data-link=&#34;https://www.juanorozco.com/?attachment_id=94&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-94&#34; srcset=&#34;https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222943/DSC09077.jpg 4643w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222943/DSC09077.jpg 300w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222943/DSC09077.jpg 768w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222943/DSC09077.jpg 1024w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222943/DSC09077.jpg 1568w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222943/DSC09077.jpg 1160w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222943/DSC09077.jpg 1740w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&#34;blocks-gallery-item&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222959/DSC09148.jpg?w=580&amp;#038;ssl=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; data-id=&#34;95&#34; data-link=&#34;https://www.juanorozco.com/?attachment_id=95&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-95&#34; srcset=&#34;https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222959/DSC09148.jpg 4050w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222959/DSC09148.jpg 300w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222959/DSC09148.jpg 768w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222959/DSC09148.jpg 1024w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222959/DSC09148.jpg 1568w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222959/DSC09148.jpg 1160w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21222959/DSC09148.jpg 1740w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&#34;blocks-gallery-item&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21223009/DSC09219.jpg?w=580&amp;#038;ssl=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; data-id=&#34;96&#34; data-link=&#34;https://www.juanorozco.com/?attachment_id=96&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-96&#34; srcset=&#34;https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21223009/DSC09219.jpg 3678w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21223009/DSC09219.jpg 300w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21223009/DSC09219.jpg 768w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21223009/DSC09219.jpg 1024w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21223009/DSC09219.jpg 1568w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21223009/DSC09219.jpg 1160w, https://m.juanorozco.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/21223009/DSC09219.jpg 1740w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used my Sony A6000 with the kit 200mm zoom lens. I would have preferred to use the Sony A7, it&#39;s full frame sensor would have let me capture the same photos with less noise. The 200mm lens I have for it doesn&#39;t seem to focus properly; it needs repair. Oh well. I like what I got from my cropped sensor camera, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided, though, that we need a telescope. And I need a 600mm prime. 😀&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Veterans Day</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2018/11/11/veterans-day/</id>
    <updated>2018-11-11T16:34:34Z</updated>
    <published>2018-11-11T16:34:34Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I remember taking the ASVAB in high school and recruiters calling me afterwards to join code breakers... apparently I showed aptitude for patterns. Goooo super ADD powers! 😂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short time later, the curiosity got to me and I went to the Marine recruiting place with questions. They showed me a video of boot camp. I thanked them for their time and never looked back. (I mean, it&#39;s called the crucible!) I learned from that video, though, to have great respect for people who CAN do those things and I defended their honor to naysayers whenever I could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;September 11th happened and I knew deep inside that I didn&#39;t have the grit to do what others did so easily. I watched as people committed themselves to something bigger than themselves, to ideals bigger than themselves. I felt shame. But like many others, I lived with it silently. Again, though, my respect for the military members grew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/res-1.cloudinary.com/dw1rz41wm/image/upload/q_auto/v1/jo-imgs/2018/11/2006-12-07-14.07.53.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Memorial in Bastogne, Belgium&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2006, my wife and I visited Bastogne, Belgium, the site of some of the worst fighting during the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_the_Bulge&#34;&gt;Battle of the Bulge&lt;/a&gt;. All over the town are memorials to sheroes and heroes. There were active duty military and their families everywhere, veterans...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wondered if somewhere in the crowd was a person returning to the place where they fought long ago. My shoes stepped in the same mud as they once did long ago. And my respect for the military service member continued to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After years and years of seeing everything that our military service members have sacrificed, the sacrifice they continue to make, and the sacrifices yet to be made, I continue to be humbled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/res-1.cloudinary.com/dw1rz41wm/image/upload/q_auto/v1/jo-imgs/2018/11/DSC00529.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Memorial in Garner, NC&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, dear Veteran. Every day, thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially to my dear friends and family...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ciriana&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Claire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staci&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Randy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Papa Hilde&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calvin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jay&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ethan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nathan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, finally, to the young man I saw at Landstuhl hospital in Germany, connected to so many machines as they rushed him into the hospital from an ambulance, thank you and I hope you made it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Snowpocalypse 2018</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2018/01/21/snowpocalypse-2018/</id>
    <updated>2018-01-21T05:15:27Z</updated>
    <published>2018-01-21T05:15:27Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The kids have been waiting for some good snow fall for two years now. The snow we got the previous week was a tease but this week&#39;s forecast really riled them up. Unfortunately, the snow kept getting pushed back and back until finally it started to snow in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2018/01/IMG_1952.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_1952&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it just wasn&#39;t sticking. It wasn&#39;t until the evening that we finally had enough snow to have some fun with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-permalink=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BeGPAZBgZbR/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;12&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:16px;&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BeGPAZBgZbR/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding: 19% 0;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&#34;&gt;&lt;svg width=&#34;50px&#34; height=&#34;50px&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 60 60&#34; version=&#34;1.1&#34; xmlns=&#34;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; xmlns:xlink=&#34;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&#34;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&#34;none&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; fill-rule=&#34;evenodd&#34;&gt;&lt;g transform=&#34;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&#34; fill=&#34;#000000&#34;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&#34;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding-top: 8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&#34;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding: 12.5% 0;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: auto;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style=&#34; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BeGPAZBgZbR/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&#34; style=&#34; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;G’night snow, see you tomorrow.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/guamaso/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Juan O&lt;/a&gt; (@guamaso) on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2018-01-18T16:24:38&#43;00:00&#34;&gt;Jan 18, 2018 at 8:24am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After snow angels, snowmen of all sizes and shapes, and an epic snowball fight, we called it a night and warmed back up.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Builds: Cat Condo and Laptop Stand</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2017/12/11/builds-cat-condo-and-laptop-stand/</id>
    <updated>2017-12-11T15:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2017-12-11T15:00:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year we purchased a Ryobi cordless tool set and a Ryobi table saw. Nothing fancy but impressive upgrades from what we had... which wasn&#39;t much!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cat Condo Project {#catcondoproject}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, we&#39;ve made the cats insulated homes from plastic totes. But they get nasty and nobody cleans them up so they eventually get tossed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, we thought of building something that can be used year round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/res.cloudinary.com/dw1rz41wm/image/upload/c_scale,w_500/v1512962328/2017-12-10_18.52.53_h7fg7t.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Cat Condo Complete&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal was not to make some beautiful piece of furniture. I&#39;m still learning so the goal was really to build something &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; and I think I met that goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The condo can accomodate insulation which means that during the summer, we can remove the insulation altogether. The door is removable and just slides into place. The &amp;quot;rooms&amp;quot; are just boxes with one side completely open. These boxes sit within the condo and are removable. That&#39;s how we access the insulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The condo also has casters so we can move it around as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used up a lot of material I had sitting in the garage and I wasn&#39;t too worried about it being square or nice to look at. I wanted to build it fast and cheap. I&#39;m really happy with how it turned out. It was a good project to cut my teeth on with the new tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next project will require a lot more precision and attention to detail...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Laptop Stand {#laptopstand}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a 2 foot by 2 foot 7-ply piece of birch plywood with the intent to build my own laptop stand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to attribute quality furniture with solid wood. But the more I learn, the more I realize quality is directly related to the attention to detail and the craftsman&#39;s skill. Plywood is cheap and stable and I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; love when the layers are taken advantage of in the design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the cat condo is done, I can direct some energy to building my laptop stand out of plywood. I have two constraints that I want to stick to: 1) take advantage of the plyood layers in the design and 2) the stand and the top should be detachable, so basiacally, the top can be used as a lapdesk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not sure how this will work out yet but there are a lot of ideas floating around. We&#39;ll see what ends up as the final design.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Four Way Test</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2017/01/29/the-four-way-test/</id>
    <updated>2017-01-29T05:20:14Z</updated>
    <published>2017-01-29T05:20:14Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately I have struggled with the America &amp;quot;I remember&amp;quot; versus the America &amp;quot;I see before me&amp;quot;. I am aware that there is a bias at work that paints my past as rosier than it really is. Still, when I run into words like these, I wonder where we stumbled:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.creativeandflow.com/images/2017/01/four-way-test.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;The Four-Way Test&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image shows the &lt;a href=&#34;http://thefourwaytest.com/history-of-the-four-way-test/&#34;&gt;Rotary&#39;s &amp;quot;Four Way Test&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;, printed on cement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Four-Way Test of the things we think, say or do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it the TRUTH?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Is it FAIR to all concerned?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Will it build GOOD WILL and BETTER FRIENDSHIPS?
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    Will it be BENEFICIAL to all concerned?
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found this etched into the side of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/place/35%C2%B035&#39;31.8%22N&#43;78%C2%B047&#39;59.0%22W/@35.592156,-78.8002672,19z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x0!8m2!3d35.592156!4d-78.79972&#34;&gt;water fountain in a random park in a small town&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Action park has two baseball diamonds, some tennis courts and a playground. It is hidden behind large warehouse buildings, straddled against an unfenced train track, hidden slightly by it&#39;s low elevation and a tall bridge. The entrance has a sharp dip down, so it is easy to miss the park as you drive by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t help but see some poetic coincidence to how relevant the string of words are today. How they are written on the side of a water fountain, one of the core elements that binds us all together regardless of what we look like or how we live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fountain is like a beacon of hope; it tries to reach out. It wants to teach us something, something we sorely need to relearn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, we have squirreled the words away to the dark and damp area that is the back of our minds.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Beach Stars</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2016/09/19/beach-stars/</id>
    <updated>2016-09-19T02:02:00Z</updated>
    <published>2016-09-19T02:02:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Beautiful night at Sunset Beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2016/09/stars-at-the-beach.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2016/09/stars-at-the-beach.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Stars at Sunset Beach&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Po the Pathfinder: origins</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2016/05/30/po-the-pathfinder/</id>
    <updated>2016-05-30T02:33:00Z</updated>
    <published>2016-05-30T02:33:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.creativeandflow.com/images/2016/03/po-the-pathfinder.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.creativeandflow.com/images/2016/03/po-the-pathfinder.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Po the Pathfinder&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I owned a VW Golf while we lived in Germany. I loved that car. It was simple. No crazy gadgets. No power steering. No air conditioning. No fuel injection. No power brakes. &lt;strong&gt;Just car.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved that car, alas, it didn&#39;t make sense to bring it back to the states with us. Unfortunately, people rarely buy those old cars so we had to junk it. My heart broke into a million pieces that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, back in the colonies, we are lucky to have added a baby to the family. This meant, though, that we were about to outgrow our 2000 Honda CR-V.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The search for a new car was on. We knew right away what type of car we needed; fuel efficient vehicle with third row seating. We narrowed it down to three contestants:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 Honda Pilot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2013&#43; Volvo XC90&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2013&#43; Nissan Pathfinder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We loved the Pilot. I preferred the boxy styling of the pre 2013 models while the newst 2016 model had some impressive safety features. Unfortunately, the older generation had pretty bad &lt;a href=&#34;http://safety.trw.com/whats-a-small-overlap-frontal-crash-test/1007/&#34;&gt;small-overlap crash&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/8SPBd108Sfc?t=33&#34;&gt;results&lt;/a&gt;. As for the new models, well, it was out of our budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve come a long way, financially, but new cars are still out of our reach for now. Which isn&#39;t a bad thing, honestly. Used cars, when properly sourced, can be a better purchase per dollar. Used cars also help educed carbon footprint and all kinds of other neat &amp;quot;green&amp;quot; stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, The Volvo XC90 is a great car. When it comes to the safety of my family, I knew the XC90 was the best fit. Unfortunately, used versions are &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; difficult to find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Nissan Pathfinder. I was a little miffed that Nissan went the route of the crossover. The Pathfinder used to be this bad ass thing of a car. Now, it had succumbed to peer pressure; it cut off its mullet and put on some khakis and polo. But, it was ok... because, in a sense, so had I.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I once owned a 300ZX, which was also a wonderful car. But, along with my Golf, those days are gone. I need a safe family car. It is part of loving someone else more than yourself; you do more for them than for yourself. And that&#39;s ok because you love the crap outta them anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I test drove the Pathfinder for the first time, there was this familiarity. The Pathfinder and I had both recently grown up. We knew each other&#39;s history because it was the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wife and I searched the interwebz and found a good option at our local CarMax. We decided on the Platinum trim because of how much we go on family trips. It was more about making our trips more comfortable and fun than anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I test drove the car and immediately decided it was meant to be. Po the Pathfinder and I understood each other; we were kindred spirits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kids gave him his name. Named after Po from Kung Fu Panda, they thought it appropriate because of how much larger the Pathfinder is compared to the last family car, the Honda CR-V. Other than Nissan being a Japanese company while Po is technically Chinese, the name kinda fits. Po the Panda becomes the Dragon Warrior and learns so much about himself, much like myself and the Pathfinder brand. It actually works out as a name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Po the Pathfinder is the newest member of the family transport. We&#39;re glad to have him. He&#39;s a fun car to drive. The styling is starting to grow on me. Let&#39;s see what kind of adventures we can get ourselves into...&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I heart pens</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2016/05/28/i-heart-pens/</id>
    <updated>2016-05-28T04:17:33Z</updated>
    <published>2016-05-28T04:17:33Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.creativeandflow.com/images/2016/03/pens.small.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;http://m.creativeandflow.com/images/2016/03/pens.large.jpg&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I have an emergent idea or thought that I need to record, I usually do it on paper. I have a subscription to Evernote, Dropbox, Google Drive. I even keep a private Github repo available for simple text notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the first place I go to mind dump is paper. Specifically, my Field Notes notebook. I love my Field Notes notebooks; they&#39;re a good size for pockets, they wear beautifully, and the paper feels great to write in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with always carrying a notebook, I always carry a pen as well. I once preferred pencil but I found them unreliable for everyday pocket reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to carry &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pilot-Precise-Retractable-Rolling-26062/dp/B001E6A9M8/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1463657160&#34;&gt;Pilot Precise click-top&lt;/a&gt;. I loved the fine line I could write with these pens. They were a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; improvement over ball point pens, in my opinion. Still, I wanted &lt;em&gt;finer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I found the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pilot-Retractable-Premium-Roller-31277/dp/B0017TMMLS/ref=sr_1_1&#34;&gt;Pilot G2 ultra fine tip&lt;/a&gt;! This little guy is pretty much my standard pen now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also enjoy using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B001CRVUPE?psc=1&#34;&gt;Zebra F-301&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Fisher-400B-Space-Bullet-Pen/dp/B000WGD13U/ref=sr_1_5&#34;&gt;Fisher Space Pen&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/uni-ball-Retractable-Translucent-12-Pack-33950/dp/B000FDR47E/ref=sr_1_1&#34;&gt;Uni-Ball Signo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the Zebra is a medium tip ball point, it still feels pretty good. I&#39;m not much of a ball point person so I don&#39;t really explore much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fisher Space Pen is just a great pocket pen. Although, I get some odd looks when I pass through security checkpoints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Uni-Ball Signo is actually very interchangeable with the G2. It really depends what I have within reach.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mind dump: The last few months</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/10/29/mind-dump-the-last-few-months/</id>
    <updated>2015-10-29T03:27:13Z</updated>
    <published>2015-10-29T03:27:13Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s interesting how life just happens. It cliché but it&#39;s true. One moment your having a margarita, the next minute you find out your little family is about to be a lot less little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mostly just want to mind dump some thoughts and maybe I&#39;ll elaborate on them later and maybe I won&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Travel {#travel}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/09/early-traveling.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/09/early-traveling.small.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Southwest Terminal - RDU&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve traveled sooo much this year for work. On the border of too much but overall it&#39;s been great. I have A-List status with Southwest which is amazing if only for the shorter security line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points are great, too. Using airline and hotel points allows us to do more fun things. We reserved a hotel in downtown Charlotte in December using nothing but points! I was looking into the point hacking which is really interesting but is also seems like a full time gig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recently got back from a month long trip visiting family back in California. It was a great time overall but it was sooo good to be home!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photography {#photography}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/09/blue-angels.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/09/blue-angels.small.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Blue Angels&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love photography. Ciri has a Sony A7 which is great but is also a bit much for me. For all my love of technology, I still prefer shooting with my Canon AE-1 Program. Unfortunately, 35mm is getting harder and harder to develop these days. Learning to do it myself is just not feasible right now, although I would love to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been thinking of getting a Sony a6000. I like the A7 full frame sensor but it&#39;s too crazy having &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; of them. As long as we can share the lenses, I&#39;m good. Although they&#39;re not fully compatible, they&#39;ll still work-ish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I&#39;ve been trying to hone my GoPro photography. It&#39;s really interesting working with the wide angle lens. It gets pretty good color and I am a huge fan of the small form factor! I&#39;m not one of their extreme user base but I&#39;ve taken it on a few outdoors-y adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kids&#43;&#43; {#kids}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found out in July that there is a baby in the oven. A total surprise but a total joyous one as well. We got to see him/her for the first time this week. This one seems to follow in big sisters footsteps, fidgety baby!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know the gender and Ciri has sent out some awesome announcements to family. It&#39;s going to be epic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;House {#house}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/09/water-heater-rusting.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/09/water-heater-rusting.small.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Rusting water heater&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got back from our trip and found out our water heater broke down. It seems to love making really hot water. Not the usual problem with water heaters but I am betting this was a precursor to a busted water heater. There is areas of rust and, after some research, it seems that our anode (piece of metal that helps keep the container from rusting) was consumed. Still have to take it apart and examine it some more but I&#39;m betting we&#39;re going to need a new one. Homeownership, for the win!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work {#work}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been super busy with work the past couple of months but I&#39;m hoping it will slow down a bit in the next couple weeks. I&#39;m really excited to put some more time back on my personal projects. Not that I&#39;m not excited about the stuff we&#39;re building at work but sustaining a sprint for this long gets a little tired. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Balloon!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/09/27/balloon/</id>
    <updated>2015-09-27T02:01:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-09-27T02:01:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ballloooonnnn... parrraaadddeeeee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/09/baloon.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/09/baloon.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Balloon&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Affogato</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/09/07/affogato/</id>
    <updated>2015-09-07T01:55:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-09-07T01:55:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Looked up the different espressos and found out about the affogato!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/09/affogato.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/09/affogato.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Affogato&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We might have a little problem…</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/09/06/we-might-have-a-little-problem/</id>
    <updated>2015-09-06T02:43:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-09-06T02:43:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So... we might have a tiny itty bitty little problem...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/09/we_might_have_a_problem.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/09/we_might_have_a_problem.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Apple items&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Chicago Noms</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/08/22/chicago-noms/</id>
    <updated>2015-08-22T02:35:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-08-22T02:35:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Chicago pizza is AMAZING, even the gluten free versions. And Firecakes? Double-y amazing with their three times gluten free chocolate donut. OM NOM NOM NOM!!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/08/chicagonoms.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/08/chicagonoms.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Lou Malnati&#39;s and Firecakes&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>M1 Abrams</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/08/17/m1-abrams/</id>
    <updated>2015-08-17T02:39:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-08-17T02:39:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Make love not war!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/08/m1abrams.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/08/m1abrams.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;M1 Abrams&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Angry Patton</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/08/17/angry-patton/</id>
    <updated>2015-08-17T01:57:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-08-17T01:57:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Coolest paint job in the collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/08/AngryPatton.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/08/AngryPatton.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Angry Patton&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The temple of FRYS…</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/08/16/the-temple-of-frys/</id>
    <updated>2015-08-16T02:36:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-08-16T02:36:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Fry&#39;s I visited in San Jose... it was... a Temple? wtf...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/08/FrysTemple.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/08/FrysTemple.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Fry&#39;s Temple&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Paddle Boarding Class</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/08/07/paddle-boarding-class/</id>
    <updated>2015-08-07T02:41:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-08-07T02:41:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wifey and I took a paddle boarding class at Lake Wheeler. Paddle boarding is harder and funner than it looks. Now we just need to save up for a board of our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/08/paddleboarding.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/08/paddleboarding.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Paddle Boarding on the lake&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Queen Safari</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/07/20/queen-safari/</id>
    <updated>2015-07-20T02:42:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-07-20T02:42:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The kids like to make her majesty as comfortable as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/queen_safari.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/queen_safari.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Guns&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Guns R Us</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/07/13/guns-r-us/</id>
    <updated>2015-07-13T02:38:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-07-13T02:38:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Cabela&#39;s: Where the bad guys in the movies shop!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, they had a P90. Who needs a P90?! I mean, SG-1 used it to explore the universe for crying out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/guns.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/guns.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Guns&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Itty bitty orange tree</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/07/08/itty-bitty-orange-tree/</id>
    <updated>2015-07-08T02:41:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-07-08T02:41:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve been getting a ton of rain lately and in just the past few weeks, my three year old potted orange tree has a ton of new growth. One more year and I might be able to let it grow fruit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/orange_tree.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/orange_tree.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Orange Tree&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>July 4th, 2015</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/07/05/july-4th-2015/</id>
    <updated>2015-07-05T02:39:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-07-05T02:39:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Using the GoPro to take some Fireworks shots. Just used a tripod and set it to Night Mode. I tripped the shutter using the iPhone app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/july4th_001.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/july4th_001.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Fireworks 1&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/july4th_002.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/july4th_002.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Fireworks 2&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/july4th_003.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/july4th_003.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Fireworks 3&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CR-V Engine rebuild</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/07/05/cr-v-engine-rebuild/</id>
    <updated>2015-07-05T02:36:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-07-05T02:36:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was just thinking about how I rebuilt the CR-V&#39;s engine today and how fun fixing, building and rebuilding things can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/crv-engine.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/crv-engine.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;CR-V Engine&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Build your own thing</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/07/04/build-your-own-thing/</id>
    <updated>2015-07-04T20:20:22Z</updated>
    <published>2015-07-04T20:20:22Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/crv-engine.large.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;CR-V Engine&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s publishings out there saying we live in a throw-away-I-want-it-now culture. &lt;strong&gt;They&#39;re probably right.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fall into that pit from time to time. I&#39;ve been known to go to the store for something I need simply because I&#39;d rather not wait the week for free shipping to delivery my item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, the majority of the time, I love the idea of fixing, rebuilding, and manufacturing my own things. I&#39;ve rebuilt car engines, replaced a scratched camera lens on my old iPhone, built my own computers, and, mostly because of my job, coded my own web things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building is power {#buildingispower}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building your own thing is empowering, fun, and challenging. It&#39;s the complete opposite of the instant gratification culture, but the payback is ten times better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The engine I rebuilt is still running. It wasn&#39;t easy. Some days I was cursing the engineers who designed it. Other days were full of heavy work. But the day I inserted the key to start the engine... oh wow... it was amazing. I was scared as hell to turn the key but when I did and the engine came back to life... I never felt so powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I could rebuild an engine, a precision machine with high tolerances, I could do &lt;strong&gt;anything&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANYTHING.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Build for building&#39;s sake {#buildforbuildingssake}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love photography, so I&#39;m building &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.juanorozco.com/tag/photoblog/&#34;&gt;my own photo blogging page&lt;/a&gt; (mainly because I prefer control over my photos but also for fun). I love audio so I&#39;ve started to research how to build my own headphones. Will I finish these projects? Who knows. Finishing isn&#39;t always the point, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build something just to build it. You might find you&#39;re not liking where your build is going. Or, maybe you need some resource you don&#39;t have access to. It is always ok to stop a project so long as you learned something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, get out there and build something, anything!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CrossFit: Day One</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/04/07/crossfit-day-one/</id>
    <updated>2015-04-07T17:33:52Z</updated>
    <published>2015-04-07T17:33:52Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/res.cloudinary.com/depnutmkm/image/upload/c_scale,w_800/v1428373890/P1010080_jr56rq.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Jelly Fish&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t like gyms, but I never knew why until today. Today was my first day doing CrossFit. Let me first get my thoughts out on CrossFit before I explain my discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CrossFit is bad ass {#crossfitisbadass}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the trainer we had. She was amazing. She was empathetic yet assertive; firm yet encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assume that this level of personal trainer is on par with many types of gyms, not specific to CrossFit “boxes” (Ohhhh, look at me! Fancy jargon in effect!). Still, she was very helpful in pointing out problems with my form during the different styles of squats. My flat-ish feet are a big problem, for example, which cause me to not push my knees outward. This attention to form will help me better myself safely and efficiently and it’s an encouraging aspect of the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workout itself, though, doesn’t feel like it’s my thing. I was trying to explain this to Ciri and I think I have it right now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I need to solve problems.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why I love climbing so much. Or trail running. I haven’t done MoveNat or Parkour, but these styles are more my thing. I like the idea of navigating terrain, there is a certain strategy and mindset involved with getting from point A to point B efficiently and quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Form is important in many, if not all workouts. Ciri believes that the act of keeping good form during extremely difficult workouts will help keep my mind engaged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;She’s probably right.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case she isn’t, though, I like that CrossFit will help me improve my fitness to a level where I can venture out to other things like climbing and parkour. These are activities that I’ve wanted to do for so long but lacked the fitness to do so and enjoy them. Actually, I was climbing for a while until I switched to CrossFit with Ciri, but I sucked at climbing. My point is, I need to start somewhere. Might as well do it where community is an integral part of the workout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cover Image {#coverimage}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took this image at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.montereybayaquarium.org/&#34;&gt;Monterey Bay Aquarium&lt;/a&gt;. Jelly Fish are neat little creatures for many reasons. I really like watching them propel themselves through the water, almost effortlessly. Just how I would like to move.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Iterations of life</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/02/16/iterations-of-life/</id>
    <updated>2015-02-16T03:36:48Z</updated>
    <published>2015-02-16T03:36:48Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.creativeandflow.com/images/2015/02/wright.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.creativeandflow.com/images/2015/02/wright_sm.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Wright Memorial - Kitty Hawk, NC&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m infatuated with the concept of iteration. As a creator of web things, I am no stranger to the concept. But as a member of society, father, husband, friend, and more; I&#39;ve noticed more and more useful applications for iteration in all aspects of life outside of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as Creative and Flow goes, I&#39;ve had goals and ideas and dreams for so long but with zero follow through. I wanted to make a web magazine on creativity in life but quickly realized how mentally taxing writing is. Coupled with trying to render this writing in a marketable way - it was too much. So I procrastinated and put off and, eventually, set it aside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would come back to Creative and Flow infrequently and post an article here or there. I would update the site to a different CMS. Sometimes I would even change the theme. Every time, hoping that the change itself was enough to spark some inspiration or jump start the drive to be consistent with the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nope.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fought with myself. On the one hand, I thought that I should just make it my &amp;quot;personal blog&amp;quot;. On the other hand I had my goals of making my own successful web magazine! Ugh. The internal war continued for a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine this isn&#39;t uncommon. We hold off on doing something because we want it to happen a specific way, all the while, never actually doing the thing and losing out on both experiences all together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I realized I was doing this, I decided it was time to give up on the start-my-own-magazine dream. It sounds harsh but being dishonest about what you&#39;re capable of is harsher. Besides, I&#39;m not giving up on writing a magazine at all; it&#39;s still on my bucket list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve learned over the past few years that creating small goals that build up to an over arching goal yields a higher success rate. Using this space for writing in order to build discipline as well as improving my writing are great first steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re making big changes in our lifestyle over the next few years and I&#39;d like to chronicle a lot of those changes. I run into problems at times and writing helps me figure out how I feel about the pending decision which is extremely helpful in making a better decision. Other times, something will tickle my fancy and I just have to share it. These ideas have all been skipped because of my apprehension over the use of this space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No more.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to sharing my thoughts. I&#39;ve got this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cover image {#coverimage}&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We visisted the Wright memorial on October of 2014 and it was one of the more beautiful places I&#39;ve been to. We stood on the ground where the first flights took place. We walked among the tools and elements the Wright brothers created because of their passion for flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used this image because it reminded of how the brothers iterated their designs and their approaches to the problems they faced. Since the day the Wright flyer left the earth, humanity has never stopped iterating on the brothers&#39; experiments.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sony PCM-M10</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/01/09/sony-pcm-m10/</id>
    <updated>2015-01-09T03:40:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-01-09T03:40:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have always loved the design of Sony products. The user interface isn&#39;t horrible but the device feels great and the audio quality is amazing. WAAYYY better than the Tascam I had before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/01/sonypcmm10.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/01/sonypcmm10.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Recorder&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Series 12</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2014/12/04/series-12/</id>
    <updated>2014-12-04T03:40:00Z</updated>
    <published>2014-12-04T03:40:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Using my Diana F&#43; with the instant back to take some photos. Thought the current series of Minifigs would be a fun object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://m.juanorozco.com/photos/2014/12/Series12&#43;-&#43;12-2014.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2014/12/Series12&#43;-&#43;12-2014.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Minifigs&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tascam recorder</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2014/11/16/tascam-recorder/</id>
    <updated>2014-11-16T03:43:00Z</updated>
    <published>2014-11-16T03:43:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tascam DP-006 recording did well. There&#39;s some slight noise but that could be the recorder itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://m.juanorozco.com/photos/2014/11/2014-11-15&#43;23.16.22.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2014/11/2014-11-15&#43;23.16.22.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Tascam&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>It’s Macaron makin’ time!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2014/11/16/its-macaron-makin-time/</id>
    <updated>2014-11-16T03:37:00Z</updated>
    <published>2014-11-16T03:37:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love this edition, the paper is water resistent making it &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; for the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://m.juanorozco.com/photos/2014/11/2014-11-16&#43;16.57.03.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2014/11/2014-11-16&#43;16.57.03.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Fud&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Macaron Take 2 – Complete Failure</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2014/07/29/macaron-take-2-complete-failure/</id>
    <updated>2014-07-29T14:59:56Z</updated>
    <published>2014-07-29T14:59:56Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/content/images/2014/Jul/2014-07-27-16-25-15.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran out of Cream of Tartar and used vinegar instead. I think my folding technique was better overall, I probably still didn&#39;t mix it enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flavor spot on which was a bummer after I made some great chocolate Ganache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am holding off more experiments until I get more confectioners sugar and cream of tartar. I didn&#39;t like that I had to use vinegar mainly because it changes my process and it&#39;s hard to find patterns when there are lots of variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I really shouldn&#39;t call this a &lt;em&gt;complete&lt;/em&gt; failure. I really shouldn&#39;t even call it a &lt;em&gt;failure&lt;/em&gt;. I got really lucky the first time which was great for my morale. With this batch not turning out as good as the first, it has shown me what &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to do. And &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; is not a failure.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Attempt the… FRENCH MACARON</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2014/07/26/attempt-the-french-macaron/</id>
    <updated>2014-07-26T05:20:00Z</updated>
    <published>2014-07-26T05:20:00Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Baking is the closest I will probably ever get to a laboratory science and I am ok with that. I love the sciences and I like laboratory science but can you eat HCl and live? Unless you have Wolverine&#39;s healing factor, I highly doubt it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baking is a one hell of a science. An unforgiving, finicky, and &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; rewarding science. Measurements often need to be precise. Heat must be applied with attention. Patience and attention to detail are key. Experimentation is &lt;strong&gt;highly&lt;/strong&gt; encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s also tasty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Today&#39;s Experiment {#todaysexperiment}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kids and I were watching &lt;a href=&#34;http://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/M14&#34;&gt;one of the Pokemon movies&lt;/a&gt; that dropped on Netflix a while back. In it was the Pokemon, Victini, swiping and munching on some of Ash and team&#39;s macarons. There&#39;s a lot of good values to get from the Pokemon movies. Friendship, teamwork, etc. What do my kids get from it? &lt;em&gt;Macarons are awesome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kids have been asking for macarons ever since. Today, I finally delivered on their desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Macaroons or Macarons? {#macaroonsormacarons}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the movie, the characters pronounce them &amp;quot;Mack-ah-rhons&amp;quot;. I always thought they were &amp;quot;mack-ah-roons&amp;quot;. Apparently both are correct... sort of. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macaroon&#34;&gt;Macaroons&lt;/a&gt; usually include coconut and are more almond based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macaroon#French&#34;&gt;Macarons&lt;/a&gt;, or French Macarons, are more of a meringue. They still have almond flour/meal but don&#39;t include coconut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the visuals in the movie, it seems like our target objective, then, is the &lt;em&gt;French Macaron&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;To the laboratory! {#tothelaboratory}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had eggs in your coffee? No? It&#39;s like coffee flavored custard - and AMAZING. But that&#39;s a recipe for another day. The convenient part is that I had some left over egg whites ready for meringue-ing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lots of tips and tricks and other voodoo for making sure you get the best macarons. When I told the kids I would make them their very own macarons, I had ZERO idea that these were &amp;quot;the hardest cookies to make&amp;quot; in all of Bakelandia. I was trolling baking websites when I found out how deep in pro french pâtissier territory I was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing something new means I was already in research mode. Finding out I was doing something &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; difficult just means I do &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; research. Before I actually made it to the kitchen, I compiled my notes and made sure I was at least semi-comfortable with the entire process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping track of these notes or just having a good capturing process is directly related to success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My Process {#myprocess}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to have my ingredients prepared before I start. I ground up the sugar, prepped all my tools, and made sure the egg whites were room temperature - that kind of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My meringue-fu is non existent so I wasn&#39;t sure what the textures and consistencies of any of the recipe&#39;s steps should be. But that is what this is all about, learning and developing the skills!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pro tip number two: Document (either mentally or on paper) the consistencies and textures at every step. Take photos. Make notes. This will help discover possible improvement opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My egg whites were clumpy and not very poofy. I probably mixed them too much. Once I added the sugar and cream of tartar, they smoothed out nicely, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The final product {#thefinalproduct}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/content/images/2014/Jul/2014-07-25-18-13-19.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first batch came out pretty good. Although most of them cracked at the top, I still call this a win; they were edible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my problems can be traced to my folding technique. I was fairly rough with the mixture and after I saw most of the macarons cracking, I looked up why. This is mostly a result of over or under mixing the dry ingredients with the egg whites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing an &amp;quot;after action review&amp;quot; helped highlight changes in my process. Compiling research notes and process notes into a central set helps this final process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Do it again {#doitagain}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next batch will be better. But I can&#39;t tackle every problem at once. I&#39;ll focus on the cracking. Although I wasn&#39;t happy with the texture of the macaron, the shell cracking is totally unacceptable. My next batch will probably focus more on my folding technique rather than the recipe. Once I get the cracking down, I&#39;ll tackle the texture. Who knows, maybe fixing one problem will fix the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is, don&#39;t feel discouraged when something doesn&#39;t come out perfect. As long as learning occured, the attempt was &lt;em&gt;not a failure&lt;/em&gt;. Just get back in there and try again. Eating the result is just as fun as &lt;em&gt;making&lt;/em&gt; the result after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/content/images/2014/Jul/2014-07-25-19-10-02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Notebooks and Index Cards</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2014/07/25/notebooks-and-index-cards/</id>
    <updated>2014-07-25T18:50:34Z</updated>
    <published>2014-07-25T18:50:34Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before &lt;a href=&#34;fieldnotesbrand.com&#34;&gt;Field Notes&lt;/a&gt; became a thing in my world, I used these awesome wire bound notebooks I bought a long time ago from the community college bookstore. I loved the green tint of the paper and the thick covers. Alas, it is impossible to stack wire bound notebooks neatly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, in the &amp;quot;Field Notes Era&amp;quot;, the smaller page count causes me to go through notebooks faster. Also, I keep reference pages in the back that I need to copy over (or tear out) with every notebook change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a problem. One that should be easily remedied either with a better process or with discipline. But, like all problems, I really need to explore the possibilities first. One thing I hear a lot about are index cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ubiquity in 3 by 5 form {#ubiquityin3by5form}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; smart people advocate the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hipster_PDA&#34;&gt;Hipster PDA&lt;/a&gt; approach and rely solely on index cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look... Index cards are boring to me. No, not the process, but the paper itself. The paper is usually a three by five cut of bright white paper printed with lightish blue tinted lines. Booooring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the Field Notes, there is no joy in writing on an index card. Sure, there&#39;s not much to innovate on with an index card - it&#39;s hard to innovate on the details when index cards lack, well... &lt;em&gt;details&lt;/em&gt;. Then again, index cards&#39; modular and mobile characteristics are desirable. Desirable enough to give them a solid try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Commit! {#commit}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a cheap-o pack of index cards at Walmart. I suppose that was a mistake. I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; have bought a nicer pack from a brand that cares about paper and the experience of writing. This is an experiment, a $3.00 experiment so far, and I can always donate them to the kids&#39; crafting supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may not come to that, though. Well, the batch I bought will &lt;strong&gt;probably&lt;/strong&gt; get donated regardless - that&#39;s how bad the paper is. But, the integration of index cards into my workflow is turning out well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s what I have discovered works for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes that I need to shared with someone (like the wife, for example) go on an index card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reference notes (like server IP&#39;s) go on an index card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything else goes in the notebook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m experimenting with keeping To Do&#39;s on the index card as well. It feels good to be able to trash the index card once the list is complete. Although, sometimes, the card may not be completed for several months - that&#39;s just how that list will go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/content/images/2014/Jul/2014-07-25-22-37-03-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole modification, though, is going well. We&#39;ll see how it continues.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Thought: Intense focus</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2014/07/21/thought-intense-focus/</id>
    <updated>2014-07-21T02:30:08Z</updated>
    <published>2014-07-21T02:30:08Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It takes years to develop and refine a skill. It takes longer still to fix a character flaw or improve a virtue. People have proven that, with proper focus, you can turn your life around. The goal is not to change but to build discipline or values that didn&#39;t exist, or barely existed, before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current thought...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intense focus on something new for one year. Immerse yourself in that thing totally. Live it. Breathe it. Allow it to consume you... then drop it after a year and move on to the next thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visualize that next year of your life with a singular goal: master this new thing. Living that year without this new thing would mean death to you. It is just one thing but it is the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What effects could this have on how you think? Or how you react to situations? The &amp;quot;thing&amp;quot; can be anything. Sewing, living in a foreign country, hermitic life, underground street fighting - something opposite to who you are or something scary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever it is, I wonder how much improvement we would see in ourselves with pure and complete focus.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Home Automata</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2014/06/05/home-automata/</id>
    <updated>2014-06-05T00:53:37Z</updated>
    <published>2014-06-05T00:53:37Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The idea of walking from one room to another, talking to your family over the phone, but not tied to a device in any way. The caller&#39;s voice travels with you to each room through speakers built into the wall. Presence sensors in each room detect your movement between rooms. A sensitive microphone also embedded in each room, but processed and cleaned up by a fancy computer somewhere in the house (so your voice doesn&#39;t sound &amp;quot;far away&amp;quot;.)... &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; is the future I remember being told was in store for us. Un-tethered and automated; &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privacy concerns have arisen, in the past few years, with recent breaches and reports. Do I really want a company to collect personal data and sell it to someone else? All under the premise that it will help automate my world? I don&#39;t think I do... but I really, &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; want that automated part!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&#39;t get much more into the privacy conversation than to just acknowledge that it is a &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; that society as a whole needs to make a decision on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is a required part of automating. Computers are dumb - take it from me, I have to program them. The more data we have on the way people use a thing, the more accurate and useful a computer can be assisting with the use of that thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Low Hanging Fruit {#lowhangingfruit}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal, for me, is to automate the silly parts of owning a home. Maintenance and purchasing are probably the low hanging fruit. Not to mention all the current products out there that handle big things well, like Nest or Nest&#39;s line of fire alarms. Still, those are pretty pricey. I&#39;m thinking about things like HVAC filters, the fridge water filters, more dish washing soap, shoes for the kids (they don&#39;t stop growing!), coffee, coconut cream, mulch for the planters... I can keep going. All these items we order consistently and regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, what we need here is data. How often do you run out of stuff? What life events may cause the average to change? Until companies open up the data you create with your shopping trips, only the companies themselves will be able to support this kind of experience which means they will only provide the experience if you shop at their store. Makes sense; they have to thrive, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, no data then. What can we without data? Well, can we at least automate the purchasing part?! Amazon doesn&#39;t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; allow this but then there are services like &lt;a href=&#34;http://zinc.io&#34;&gt;Zinc.io&lt;/a&gt; that work with business to automate purchases so it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; possible. Sweet. All we need to do is to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a long ways away from walking around my house with true hands-free and voice activated automation - it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It&#39;s a good time to be a nerd {#itsagoodtimetobeanerd}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greatest part of the Internet-of-Things/home automation mindset is that it hit a golden age of interest and output. More and more companies are wrapping their little capitalist fingers around the idea and pumping out useful (sometimes) products. Uber-nerds, like myself, are smitten with products like Raspberry Pi, Beagleboard, and Arduino. These little &amp;quot;Maker&amp;quot; specials are &lt;strong&gt;wondrous&lt;/strong&gt; tools of mass nerdiness. My point is, if I was trying to make one, home automation is BACK! 😀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a great example of the kind of experiences I am talking about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/87522764?color=ffffff&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/87522764&#34;&gt;Cloudwash: the connected washing machine&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/bergstudio&#34;&gt;Berg&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The key to success with Evernote</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2013/03/15/the-key-to-success-with-evernote/</id>
    <updated>2013-03-16T01:47:58Z</updated>
    <published>2013-03-16T01:47:58Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve switched organization styles numerous times with my notes over the years.  Through every change, though, only the search engine maintains my sanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing how it works is important, but you can get by with basic understanding of search concepts.  For people wanting to make Evernote &amp;quot;work&amp;quot; for them or for people like me (fanboy to the core) who just want to learn how to use searching more efficiently, reading the Evernote Search doc is key to success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dev.evernote.com/documentation/cloud/chapters/search_grammar.php&#34;&gt;Evernote Search Grammar - Evernote Developers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Photoblog – Looked bigger on Amazon photo…</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2013/03/08/photoblog-looked-bigger-on-amazon-photo/</id>
    <updated>2013-03-08T23:49:50Z</updated>
    <published>2013-03-08T23:49:50Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;https://i1.wp.com/farm9.staticflickr.com/8511/8540978204_2c9f7af015_b.jpg?w=580&#39; style=&#39;max-width:600px;&#39; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
  &lt;div&gt;
    Lego notebook has a few pages left. Ciri ordered me a reporter soft cover. We both thought it was the large... Oh well, when it comes to notebooks, it&#39;s win-win!&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
  via Flickr http://flic.kr/p/e1JKfU
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Photoblog – Breakfast for lunch</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2013/03/02/photoblog-breakfast-for-lunch/</id>
    <updated>2013-03-02T17:06:44Z</updated>
    <published>2013-03-02T17:06:44Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;https://i1.wp.com/farm9.staticflickr.com/8229/8522135610_f3f16f7f7d_b.jpg?w=580&#39; style=&#39;max-width:600px;&#39; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
  &lt;div&gt;
    Chorizo and egg patties with provolone, bacon, and grilled onions. Didnt have lettuce or tomatoes - would have sealed the deal... &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
  via Flickr http://flic.kr/p/dZ5b1A
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hero Rush 5K Obstacle Mud Run – Planned</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2013/01/26/hero-rush-5k-obstacle-mud-run-planned/</id>
    <updated>2013-01-27T04:03:42Z</updated>
    <published>2013-01-27T04:03:42Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;http://www.herorush.com/events/carolinas-charlotte/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one looks tough... I can&#39;t wait!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still making sure we can run this one, so marking it as planned for now.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Ninja Challenge Obstacle 5k – Scheduled</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2013/01/26/the-ninja-challenge-obstacle-5k/</id>
    <updated>2013-01-27T03:47:57Z</updated>
    <published>2013-01-27T03:47:57Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You can&#39;t say you&#39;re a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theninjachallenge.com/&#34;&gt;ninja until you complete this 5k obstacle/mud run&lt;/a&gt;.  I did two mud runs last year, this one and Rugged Maniac.  Both were difficult in their own way, but the Ninja run required WAY more upper body strength - of which I had NONE.  I had failed two of the obstacles because of my lack of ninja-ness.  To my credit, though, I was the only one (in our little group) that was able to scale the wall jump (my upper body strength has a huganticly slow casting speed and an even longer cool-down).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year will be different. I&#39;ve been working out the upper body and I&#39;ve lost a lot of weight. This year, Juan becomes a certified Ninja.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ninja run is in Fuquay-Varina - a short drive from my place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year&#39;s track was perilous (mud climb was almost impossible, water run was weird, and one of the wall scale was broken) for the later heats. We intend on taking an earlier heat to take advantage of a fresh track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re hoping to get a large-ish group this  year.  Aside from the Hero Run, I think this is going to be the toughest obstacle run this year. Running with a bigger group means more &lt;del&gt;yelling&lt;/del&gt; encouragement and more help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m excited. May 18th.  This should be four of &lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.wordpress.com/category/events/5k-events/&#34;&gt;my six committed 5K&#39;s&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of arm and core exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run/walk... over 20 obstacles, though.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Commitment Day 5k – Completed</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2013/01/26/commitment-day-5k/</id>
    <updated>2013-01-27T03:34:35Z</updated>
    <published>2013-01-27T03:34:35Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;January 1st 5k. I hit the new year running... literally. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.commitmentday.com/&#34;&gt;Commitment Day run was number one&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.wordpress.com/category/events/5k-events/&#34;&gt;six committed 5k&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; for this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run/walked the 5 kilos in about 36:39.9 minutes (I started the timer late, but ended it late as well.) This run was great. It was a beautiful run through downtown (I love the rain) and it really set the tone for me. Five kilometers isn&#39;t a big deal, really. But the commitment of actually going out of my comfort zone and doing them is the important part. Most of the remaining six runs will be mud/obstacle runs - these tend to be funner and more exciting. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following field notes were typed into my phone after the race. I tried to remember my thoughts in order...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Field Notes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cold, wet morning. Parked at Dan Allen deck thinking parking near start line would be impossible. Parking AFTER the start line was indeed packed. Parking before the start line was abundant. Met Dan, old coworker and good friend. He&#39;s in better shape than I am - he visits the gym regularly. Brought a water-proofish jacket. Bad idea... it&#39;s too thick. Checked in at booth and picked up bib. No timing chip. 🙁 A lot of people of different age ranges. Seeing lots of pre teens which makes me envious. I can&#39;t wait to run one of these with the kiddos when they&#39;re older.  Meandering over to the start line. Being told to get BEHIND the start line.  Probably a good idea. Started and Dan is a good deal faster than I am. Should have brought headphones. I brought my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.olloclip.com/&#34;&gt;olloclip&lt;/a&gt; thinking we were going to be doing more walking than running (another friend of ours bailed out at the last minute... -__- ). Instead, it is weighing my jacket down.  Raleigh police officers are watching traffic at intersections. Saying good morning to as many as I can. I imagine they would rather be doing other things.  The route has changed; we are heading to city hall? I think.  Taking photos of interesting things. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/juanthedesigner/tags/commitmentday/&#34;&gt;Uploading to flickr&lt;/a&gt; when possible.  Trying to pick out people in the crowd and race in secret with them. Most of them are winning. Sprinted the last leg. Finished in about 36.5 minutes. Not bad for me. Sprinting hurt, though. Heading home. Rain is going to get worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media from my run&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/juanthedesigner/tags/commitmentday/&#34;&gt;Flickr photos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.motionx.com/gps/dl.php?file=http://share.gps.motionxlive.com/shr/x/kmz/61fc74f10fa801835c553f0df46a8fe8&amp;amp;name=Commitment%20Day.kmz&#34;&gt;GPS track in KMZ.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Color Mania 5k – Scheduled</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2013/01/26/color-mania-5k/</id>
    <updated>2013-01-27T02:57:51Z</updated>
    <published>2013-01-27T02:57:51Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not to be confused with &lt;a href=&#34;http://thecolorrun.com/&#34;&gt;Color Run&lt;/a&gt;, Color Mania is hosting their own color run in April.  Ciri and I are signed up and we will be bringing the kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://colormania5k.com/raleigh-color-run/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be number two of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Guamaso/status/277069924508246016&#34;&gt;committed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.wordpress.com/category/events/5k-events/&#34;&gt;six 5Ks this year&lt;/a&gt;.  It depends on if/when the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2012/04/10/automattics-worldwide-wp-5k/&#34;&gt;WordPress 5k&lt;/a&gt; will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Info:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run/walk from what read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You get color thrown at you. 😀&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Photoblog – Pencils!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2013/01/22/photoblog-pencils/</id>
    <updated>2013-01-22T19:30:08Z</updated>
    <published>2013-01-22T19:30:08Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;https://i0.wp.com/farm9.staticflickr.com/8508/8406692186_8a22c67b2e_b.jpg?w=580&#39; style=&#39;max-width:600px;&#39; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
  &lt;div&gt;
    How I&#39;ve missed these pencils...&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
  via Flickr http://flic.kr/p/dNSuGJ
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My harvest</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/11/22/my-harvest/</id>
    <updated>2012-11-23T02:00:32Z</updated>
    <published>2012-11-23T02:00:32Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As Ciri, the kiddos, and I continue on this path of a healthy, sustainable lifestyle, I am reminded now more than ever about what Thanksgiving was and what it has changed in to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year has proven difficult yet the harvest of our hard work has been plentiful and nourishing. Between doing what I love with friends that I care about and living a beautiful life with some of the coolest people on the planet, its hard to find something to NOT be thankful for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The years have been rough and stormy and I could sit here and write about all of the harsh moments that could have been better. In truth, the near future looks promising and THAT is what is important. Hard work and hard decisions bring the largest and most bountiful harvest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surrounding yourself with people that are supportive, respectful, understanding, and humorous doesn&#39;t hurt either. Sometimes, hard decisions and hard work sucks, but they&#39;re mere presence helps make it easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m thankful for my family and friends. I&#39;m also thankful that my hard work returned a great year with my family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I just heard th…</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/09/23/i-just-heard-th/</id>
    <updated>2012-09-23T19:25:48Z</updated>
    <published>2012-09-23T19:25:48Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just heard the A-Team song. Feel like building defenses for the house in case a corrupt sheriff/drug dealer/dictator/etc comes to harass my family.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Photoblog – Microwave poached eggs</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/09/01/photoblog-microwave-poached-eggs/</id>
    <updated>2012-09-01T15:09:40Z</updated>
    <published>2012-09-01T15:09:40Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;https://i1.wp.com/farm9.staticflickr.com/8462/7906996696_abc98f9f08_b.jpg?w=580&#39; style=&#39;max-width:600px;&#39; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  Looked scary. Tasted fine. &gt;.&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
  &lt;p&gt;
    via Flickr http://flic.kr/p/d3HqDf
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Photoblog – It’s probably true</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/09/01/photoblog-its-probably-true/</id>
    <updated>2012-09-01T15:09:36Z</updated>
    <published>2012-09-01T15:09:36Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;https://i0.wp.com/farm9.staticflickr.com/8036/7906994960_077b159cba_b.jpg?w=580&#39; style=&#39;max-width:600px;&#39; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    via Flickr http://flic.kr/p/d3Hq8j
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evernote Moleskine – English – Evernote Trunk</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/08/25/evernote-moleskine-english-evernote-trunk/</id>
    <updated>2012-08-25T15:53:17Z</updated>
    <published>2012-08-25T15:53:17Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://trunk.evernote.com/gear/evernote-moleskine&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/6287943768d3d8ae518a453f15e086df_300_199_c1.png?w=580&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
  I don&#39;t care much for the &#34;smart&#34; features, but I will need another notebook soon!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://trunk.evernote.com/gear/evernote-moleskine&#34;&gt;Evernote Moleskine - English - Evernote Trunk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Using Dropbox for versioning</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/08/07/using-dropbox-for-versioning/</id>
    <updated>2012-08-08T02:37:39Z</updated>
    <published>2012-08-08T02:37:39Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Prior to my current position, I had no clue what SVN or GIT were.  I finally got a very thorough explanation of SVN and versioning in general a few weeks ago.  Like all concepts I learn, I started to examine areas that might benefit from not just SVN but the concept of versions and revisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obvious place was my personal pool of ongoing projects.  But I know how I work with new things.  I get all “ooo shiny” and want to find a place for it even thought all it is is shiny – nothing more. With this in mind, I thought about where my projects currently reside: Dropbox. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Versioning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dropbox has revisions!  Duh!  Using the methods explained to me but considering the size and use of my files, Dropbox is the perfect platform. I have accumulated about 4 gigs of extra space on my free account over the years; It already creates periodic revisions (&lt;strike&gt;I don’t believe it’s with every save, but that’s ok for my use&lt;/strike&gt; it is with “every change”); and it syncs to all my other computers including my test server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The test server, by the way, has symbolic links set up so when I save the file locally, it is immediately pushed to my web server for testing. No FTP required!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Research is for weenies.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t think to search if anyone already thought about this until recently.  Maybe I’m not searching with the right query, but I couldn&#39;t find much except “Hey! Here’s an idea!” which is less than helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did start reading up on the concepts behind SVN and GIT which helped a little.  Wiki: saving the day again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Update] I just found this link. I don’t have a problem with rollbacks but most of my projects are small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/8238399/dropbox-as-a-programmers-source-control&#34;&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/8238399/dropbox-as-a-programmers-source-control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[/Update]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SVN THIS!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a web application that I am updating: DailyKittehEmail App.  The current stable version is 1.0 while the current development version I call RC. So the folder structure looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WEBAPPS &amp;gt; DailyKittehEmail  &amp;gt; 1.0, RC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The versioned folders are locked – I don’t edit those anymore. If I need to make an update, I copy the whole folder to an RC folder and work from there – this is how I branch or fork a version.  When I’m ready to commit that release, I give it a version based on the edits made and change the folder name to the new version number. The new folder structure will look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WEBAPPS &amp;gt; DailyKittehEmail &amp;gt; 1.0, 1.1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During development, though, as I finish editing for the night, I update my release notes with that nights version number.  Discipline, lads and laddettes, discipline. The folder would stay as RC but I keep the log going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the cycle continues.  If I need to update 1.1, I copy it into a new RC folder and squash bugs or add new cool stuff.  The best part is that all this is done within Dropbox so it’s backed up and versioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meh. What about source control.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing it needs is source control.  Because it’s just myself, I don’t really run into me overwriting my own changes because I didn’t properly check something out/in.  But to make this a valid solution, it would obviously need some way of controlling edits and commits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another necessity would be to create a copy with every save.  The source control can back up the file before overwriting it to a specified folder in the Dropbox space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, it’s not very robust on it’s own, but it’s free and it’s robust &lt;em&gt;enough&lt;/em&gt; for a one-dev gig.  With some proper planning, it can probably work with multiples but why when SVN is pretty cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Update]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, apparently this helps with source control&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tortoisehg.bitbucket.org/&#34;&gt;http://tortoisehg.bitbucket.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[/Update]&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tactus Technology Can Make Physical Buttons Rise Up Out of Touchscreens – Core77</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/07/29/tactus-technology-can-make-physical-buttons-rise-up-out-of-touchscreens-core77/</id>
    <updated>2012-07-30T01:01:52Z</updated>
    <published>2012-07-30T01:01:52Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.core77.com/blog/ux/tactus_technology_can_make_physical_buttons_rise_up_out_of_touchscreens_23029.asp&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0tactus02.jpg?w=580&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibilities of this are astounding.  Obviously some sort of braille reader.  It&#39;s not very dynamic (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tactustechnology.com/technology.html&#34;&gt;it can only have one set of buttons at a time, apparently&lt;/a&gt;) but just from a quick conversation, I&#39;m thinking Apple could use this to completely remove all the buttons on the iphone. For example, the volume buttons don&#39;t do anything in certain situations. With this technology, the buttons would be gone in these situations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.core77.com/blog/ux/tactus_technology_can_make_physical_buttons_rise_up_out_of_touchscreens_23029.asp&#34;&gt;Tactus Technology Can Make Physical Buttons Rise Up Out of Touchscreens - Core77&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hunger Games music and other soundtracks on Amazon</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/07/04/hunger-games-music-and-other-soundtracks-on-amazon/</id>
    <updated>2012-07-05T00:17:01Z</updated>
    <published>2012-07-05T00:17:01Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;figure style=&#34;width: 280px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34;&gt;[&lt;img title=&#34;Hunger Games Cover&#34; src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/51LG%2BEyHAFL._SL500_AA280_.jpg?resize=280%2C280&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;280&#34; height=&#34;280&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;figcaption class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;Hunger Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/feature.html/ref=bt_atcg_mine_cta?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;docId=1000803791&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;amp;pf_rd_s=center-2&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=1DWMJ1E7C8KPJN8NNDRV&amp;amp;pf_rd_t=101&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=1375321842&amp;amp;pf_rd_i=163856011&#34;&gt;Amazon has a good selection of $2.99 soundtracks&lt;/a&gt; right now, one them being &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Hunger-Games-District-Beyond/dp/B007IGNG6O/ref=br_lf_m_1000803791_1_1_ttl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=dmusic&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=1373924342&amp;amp;pf_rd_s=center-2&amp;amp;pf_rd_t=1401&amp;amp;pf_rd_i=1000803791&amp;amp;pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=0R5EBGM1R53Y70E0YD75&#34;&gt;The Hunger Games: Songs from District 12 and Beyond.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A man and his keyboard</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/07/04/a-man-and-his-keyboard/</id>
    <updated>2012-07-04T20:56:13Z</updated>
    <published>2012-07-04T20:56:13Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Almost a year ago I bought a new keyboard.  Not just any old QWERTY styled piece of plastic... no no - a solar powered wonder of technology.  Countless number of lines coded.  Thousands of emails written.  Numerous facerolls committed. Yet here we are - still ticking and kicking ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Logitech-Wireless-Solar-Keyboard-K750/dp/B004MF11MU/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1341435305&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=k750&#34;&gt;Logitech K750&lt;/a&gt; - very thin and solar powered.  The only thing that would make this better would be a palm-heat powered mouse to go with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love my keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New project notebooks</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/06/06/new-project-notebooks/</id>
    <updated>2012-06-06T23:57:16Z</updated>
    <published>2012-06-06T23:57:16Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/20120606-205549.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/20120606-205549.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20120606-205549.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cahiers filled up and, honestly, they were too small for what I was using them for. Still, learned a lot on what works for me.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Moleskine through an Olloclip</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/05/18/moleskine-through-an-olloclip/</id>
    <updated>2012-05-18T23:41:10Z</updated>
    <published>2012-05-18T23:41:10Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120518-193959.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120518-193959.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20120518-193959.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macro lens.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Homemade Os</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/05/12/homemade-os/</id>
    <updated>2012-05-13T01:27:03Z</updated>
    <published>2012-05-13T01:27:03Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120512-212534.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120512-212534.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20120512-212534.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turned to be big. Filling needs work, too runny.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Big Jambox is a big meh, that’s what it is…</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/05/09/big-jambox-is-a-big-meh-thats-what-it-is/</id>
    <updated>2012-05-10T02:23:12Z</updated>
    <published>2012-05-10T02:23:12Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/video-placeholder.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-2937&#34; title=&#34;Black Big Jambox&#34; src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/video-placeholder.jpg?w=300&amp;#038;resize=300%2C198&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;198&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It is odd to me that the designer of the Jambox also designed the new Big Jambox.  The Jambox is simple and almost utilitarian.  The Big Jambox with it&#39;s Jawbone badge and extra buttons and extra options is not the same.  I wouldn&#39;t even agree if you said it was an &amp;quot;evolutionary step&amp;quot; in the design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I can see how the extra controls would be useful.  The buttons have context just by their shape and positioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But... that badge.  Oohhh, that badge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved that the original covertly mentioned it was a Jawbone product on top.  The product design sets this speaker apart from it&#39;s competitors - why do you need to have your mark on the front of it as well?  It pulls attention away from the detail and thought that went into the design. Keep it simple, a gentle reminder would suffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything, I bet it sounds pretty bad ass, though.  More air space, bigger drivers, more powah.  Obviously, I&#39;m conflicted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, I&#39;m not: I heart my Jambox. Just bummed out on the design of this iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jawbone.com/speakers/bigjambox/overview&#34;&gt;Jawbone BIG JAMBOX Wireless Speaker | Hi-fi Sound, Wireless, Portable, Smart &amp;amp; Updateable&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My First 5K / Mud Run</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/04/23/my-first-5k-mud-run/</id>
    <updated>2012-04-24T03:21:57Z</updated>
    <published>2012-04-24T03:21:57Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Entering the Rugged Maniac is one of the craziest things I’ve ever done.  I have never pushed myself so hard for so long under this amount of soreness and pain. In hindsight, I don’t think I pushed myself that hard but the race was something I never thought I’d ever do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started training with Ciri, I had lots of questions regarding training and the race itself.  Is there a type of shoe that helps keep footing more than others?  What kind of training has a better success rate?  Can we actually finish?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The questions now feel somewhat naïve. We attempted a couch to 5K program and did okay, we actually didn’t finish it by race day.  We used our Vibram Five Finger KSO and had NO traction… but neither did anyone else. Mud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course you will finish.  You can walk the entire time, skip every obstacle if you want, although not sure why you would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What I learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important part I learned from this whole ordeal, was to have fun.  Make friends, enjoy the mud and the outdoors, and don’t worry about your time.  It was, honestly, like being a kid again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we were checking in our bag, I overheard two people complaining over how slow others were and how they got in the way.  This was really off-putting until we were out on the track.  During our heat, we met two guys that were just a little faster than us as first. We were able to catch up to them after a while and we sort of stuck together. We ended up motivating each other, helping each other past obstacles, and hooting and hollering when we passed the mile markers. Mick and Eric, you guys rock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obstacles were fun except one: the barb wire hill.  That thing was nasty.  &lt;strong&gt;Bring something to protect your knees.&lt;/strong&gt;  The sharp rock tore my knees and shins to shreds.  Once the hill was passed, though, there is a wave of amazement and accomplishment.  Yea, you’re playing in mud and climbing hills, but it’s not easy. It’s fun, yet difficult, but rewarding nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Preparation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/img_0457.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;background-image:none;border-bottom:0;border-left:0;margin:0 10px 10px 0;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;float:left;border-top:0;border-right:0;padding-top:0;&#34; title=&#34;IMG_0457&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_0457&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/img_0457_thumb.jpg?resize=181%2C242&#34; width=&#34;181&#34; height=&#34;242&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The couch to 5k is all running.  My legs felt fine after the run, the soreness is all upper body, back, and butt. Granted, I slipped in the mud and fell on my ass a lot, we should have still done more core or upper body stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you train for obstacles when there aren’t any in your home, though.  We could probably hang a rope on a tree for climbing exercises, which would have helped A LOT, most of what we needed was endurance and core stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Packing for the race wasn’t too big of a deal.  Spare clothes, towels, minor toiletries, etc.  Bring sandals – if you can spare your shoes, donate them, they’ll be really muddy anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t go too overboard with running clothes. If you wear shorts, protect the knees.  Simple shirt will suffice provided it’s lightweight and won’t take on fifty pounds of mud. I spent about $70 at Target on spandex undershorts, a running shirt and some simple shorts.  They cleaned up pretty good and even if they didn’t, they still work as simple exercise clothes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard the early heats were bogged down by the massive amount of people running. Our heat was second to last and was very empty.  I would do that again because it removes that added pressure of getting in people’s way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring a friend.  Bring LOTS of friends.  We met a father that was easily in his fifties.  He brought his “boys” this time around and their whole pack finished waay ahead of us. How cool is it to be in shape to not only run this thing but also keep up with your kids.  Motivating each other and just having a blast. Friggin’ awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ciri and I had each other.  If I fell, she was there if I needed help.  On the 12 foot walls, I helped her over.  Our friends Mick and Eric were great motivators and good sports.  To also have friends and family in the crowd though, would be great as well.  There was lots of stuff to keep kids entertained as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sprint that last turn.&lt;/strong&gt;  You’ve done just over three miles of obstacles, mud, sweat, and blood.  You can sprint that last 100 ft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shoes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/img_0459.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;background-image:none;border-bottom:0;border-left:0;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;border-top:0;border-right:0;padding-top:0;&#34; title=&#34;IMG_0459&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_0459&#34; src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/img_0459_thumb.jpg?resize=348%2C260&#34; width=&#34;348&#34; height=&#34;260&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ciri got me into the minimalist shoes.  I’ve always loved being barefoot so these shoes make sense to me.  After reading up on the “barefoot movement” they have taken up more of my life than I thought they would.  They take some getting used to, but they feel really good once you’re broken in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have the Vibram Five Finger KSOs which I realized aren’t very good for trails, let alone mud runs.  Still, they held their own and are currently getting a well deserved wash.  The sole is very smooth for track or streets and does ok for grass or very mild trails. They felt REALLY good, though and being able to shake the mud off easily was fairly advantageous. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next run will definitely warrant the purchase of a new pair specifically for trail runs – we’ll see if they offer better traction. I know mud negates a lot of special treads but even preventing one fall will keep my butt happier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Memories&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/img_2857.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;background-image:none;border-bottom:0;border-left:0;margin:0 10px 10px 0;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;float:left;border-top:0;border-right:0;padding-top:0;&#34; title=&#34;IMG_2857&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_2857&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/img_2857_thumb.jpg?resize=181%2C242&#34; width=&#34;181&#34; height=&#34;242&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I’m all about memories and the experience. We met some cool people, took some scary spills, overcame many fears and pains, and took on a challenge we never thought we could.  I honestly see things differently: if I can do this, what else can I do?  What more adventures can I find? How much farther can I push myself? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would much rather run on trails than on pavement or tracks so, for me, the experience was about enjoying the outdoors and playing in the mud. It was also about conquering obstacles of the track and of ourselves. It might sound silly to career marathon runners, but this was an amazing experience for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that others will be motivated to try a mud run of their own.  It’s not easy, but it’s worth every drop of blood and every muscle ache.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Vibrams after Rugged Maniac</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/04/21/vibrant-after-rugged-maniac/</id>
    <updated>2012-04-22T01:01:51Z</updated>
    <published>2012-04-22T01:01:51Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/20120421-220059.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/20120421-220059.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20120421-220059.jpg&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;ll do shoes. That&#39;ll do.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Real or not real…</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/04/14/real-or-not-real/</id>
    <updated>2012-04-15T03:52:47Z</updated>
    <published>2012-04-15T03:52:47Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/20120414-235116.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/20120414-235116.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20120414-235116.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finished Hunger games and felt inspired. Almost done, I want to take my time on the primrose and locket.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Moleskine Thoughts</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/04/07/moleskine-thoughts/</id>
    <updated>2012-04-07T20:54:45Z</updated>
    <published>2012-04-07T20:54:45Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; title=&#34;My Moleskines&#34; src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/farm8.staticflickr.com/7188/6908568532_afa41c9eec_n.jpg?resize=239%2C320&#34; alt=&#34;My Moleskines&#34; width=&#34;239&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;My first Moleskine was a sketchbook with the thick slightly yellowish pages.  I love that notebook, but I felt it was too nice for daily stuff.  Target has some of their Moleskines on clearence so I picked up a pocket lined and a regular lined notebook. I also pre-ordered Lego branded plain Moleskine when they were announced.  I realized something in the past month... Moleskine&#39;s paper quality sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been using my Lego Moleskine for a month now - jotting ideas, keeping project notes, sketches, et al. I use a Pilot V5 pen and I borrowed a friends fountain pen too - both leak through the page enough that I can&#39;t use the back page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My lined notebook from Target is slightly better, but not by much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t get it.  This is what Picasso used?  I&#39;m being sarcastic, I know the two products are not the same. Still, it&#39;s frustrating to find out that these wonderful notebook&#39;s use sub-par paper.  I&#39;m bummed.  Partly because I love the form factor and the simplicity and the ubiquitousness of the notebooks.  But mostly because now I have to finish the notebook before I try something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://blackcover.net/&#34;&gt;website has been helpful with researching my new future notebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lego Moleskine!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/03/21/lego-moleskine/</id>
    <updated>2012-03-21T16:57:30Z</updated>
    <published>2012-03-21T16:57:30Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/20120321-125649.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/20120321-125649.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20120321-125649.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Little Printer – Almost a personal thermal printer</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2012/03/04/little-printer-almost-a-personal-thermal-printer/</id>
    <updated>2012-03-04T20:05:24Z</updated>
    <published>2012-03-04T20:05:24Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bergcloud.com/littleprinter/&#34;&gt;Little Printer | BERG Cloud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://bergcloud.com/littleprinter/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/todo.jpe&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
  I want one of these, but only if I can print my own content to it.  I can imagine many uses for it at work for use in our current workflow.  I can think of even more uses for this at home... to do lists, meal plan/menu...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
  What about giving one to parents? I can print out things remotely about the kids and stuff.  Can&#39;t do that right now, it seems, as it looks like they have it locked down.  It&#39;s not a printer per se.  Still, beautiful delivery of another method to consuming online content.
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Listening to… Studio 360, American Icons: I Love Lucy</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/12/10/listening-to-studio-360-american-icons-i-love-lucy/</id>
    <updated>2011-12-10T18:37:05Z</updated>
    <published>2011-12-10T18:37:05Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Getting caught up on  Studio 360&#39;s American Icons series.  When they play clips from the show, I recall the episodes and start laughing slightly as I remember how funny the show was.  Can&#39;t wait for the enjoy it again with the kids when they are older.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.studio360.org/2011/aug/05/&#34;&gt;http://www.studio360.org/2011/aug/05/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Screenshot- iTunes Match</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/11/24/screenshot-itunes-match/</id>
    <updated>2011-11-24T18:44:42Z</updated>
    <published>2011-11-24T18:44:42Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/20111124-134238.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/20111124-134238.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20111124-134238.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yea...&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Are all those options on newer cars needed?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/10/30/are-all-those-options-on-newer-cars-needed/</id>
    <updated>2011-10-31T00:19:08Z</updated>
    <published>2011-10-31T00:19:08Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/stscpanel.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-bottom:0;border-left:0;display:inline;margin-left:0;border-top:0;margin-right:0;border-right:0;&#34; title=&#34;STSCPanel&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;STSCPanel&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/stscpanel_thumb.jpg?resize=244%2C163&#34; width=&#34;244&#34; height=&#34;163&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I love this image of the Space Shuttle&#39;s cockpit.  So many controls and screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reminds of newer cars though, and not in a good way.  On the shuttle, the plethora of controls makes sense. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first car didn’t have a digital radio – I installed one afterwards.  The A/C had those slider switches.  Now, A/C controls have many variations, multiplied by the number of passengers – since they all have their own environment controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cars are getting closer and closer to the complexity of a space craft. Instead of making them simpler and smarter, we&#39;re making them more reliant on our feedback. The logical progression isn&#39;t more options of high techy-ness, but towards &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_driverless_car&#34;&gt;autonomy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Late hours on the computer</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/10/09/late-hours-on-the-computer/</id>
    <updated>2011-10-09T13:04:44Z</updated>
    <published>2011-10-09T13:04:44Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I wake up early to get a jump on work, one of my favorite moments is when my monitor’s brightness changes as the sun comes up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href=&#34;http://stereopsis.com/flux/&#34;&gt;F.Lux&lt;/a&gt; installed because I do a lot of stuff either really late or really early.  When F.Lux brightens my screen in the morning, it’s almost like a happy cup of coffee; like watching the sun come up but not knowing you were waiting for it. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>$120 part… In the palm of your hand.</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/10/02/120-part-in-the-palm-of-your-hand/</id>
    <updated>2011-10-02T13:55:09Z</updated>
    <published>2011-10-02T13:55:09Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/20111002-095250.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/20111002-095250.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20111002-095250.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could have cost me $210 installed. Man, I&#39;m glad my dad taught me about repairing my own car.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>50k words, or bust.</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/09/25/50k-words-or-bust/</id>
    <updated>2011-09-26T03:00:48Z</updated>
    <published>2011-09-26T03:00:48Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m preparing for &lt;a href=&#34;http://go.jzo.me/nnwm&#34;&gt;NaNoWriMo&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully, using Evernote and as well as being better prepared, I will write those 50,000 words. I&#39;ve got some notes ready as well as a few ideas of what to write about, but haven&#39;t decided yet. Perfect excuse to try this poll feature...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;pd_a_5533392&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;CSS_Poll PDS_Poll&#34; id=&#34;PDI_container5533392&#34; style=&#34;display:inline-block;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;PD_superContainer&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://polldaddy.com/p/5533392&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Take Our Poll&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/noscript&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Miyazaki Effect</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/09/25/the-miyazaki-effect/</id>
    <updated>2011-09-25T22:52:02Z</updated>
    <published>2011-09-25T22:52:02Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kids watching Howl&#39;s Moving Castle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/20110925-075149.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/20110925-075149.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20110925-075149.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I love this kind of stuff.</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/09/24/i-love-this-kind-of-stuff/</id>
    <updated>2011-09-25T01:12:54Z</updated>
    <published>2011-09-25T01:12:54Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love how shorts can have as much emotion, plot, and feeling as a full length movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;embed-vimeo&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/28043193&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/28043193&#34;&gt;Danger Planet&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/user7884352&#34;&gt;Justin Burks&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Door stop – It’s the little things…</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/09/17/door-stop-its-the-little-things/</id>
    <updated>2011-09-17T05:24:49Z</updated>
    <published>2011-09-17T05:24:49Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://dornob.com/right-angle-foot-free-hand-deployed-doorstop-invention/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/door-stopper-built-in.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I love about design, it fixes problems you didn&#39;t realize you had until something comes along that makes you say, &amp;quot;Well, yea... why wasn&#39;t it done that way before?&amp;quot;  The one thing I would say about this is the handle needs some sort of tactile feedback to let the user know the stop has popped out.  It lets the user know how to retract the stop, but it needs to be tactile as well.  Other than that, love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dornob.com/right-angle-foot-free-hand-deployed-doorstop-invention/&#34;&gt;Right Angle: Foot-Free, Hand-Deployed Doorstop Invention | Designs &amp;amp; Ideas on Dornob&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Droool… nerd blueprints…</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/08/07/droool-nerd-blueprints/</id>
    <updated>2011-08-08T01:41:36Z</updated>
    <published>2011-08-08T01:41:36Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theblueprintsbook.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/homespread_1_rev.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not a Star Wars nerd, I love the movies but I don&#39;t really care who shot first nor do I give a crap about the hatred towards Jar-jar. But give me blueprints and watch the nerdgasm flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theblueprintsbook.com/&#34;&gt;Star Wars: The Blueprints&lt;/a&gt;. via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dudecraft.com/2011/07/nerdgasm-star-wars-blueprints.html&#34;&gt;Dudecraft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Socializing socialness with a watch?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/08/01/socializing-socialness-with-a-watch/</id>
    <updated>2011-08-02T00:04:12Z</updated>
    <published>2011-08-02T00:04:12Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yankodesign.com/2011/07/11/watch-encourages-play/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/moosh_01.jpg?w=580&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid, I remember gimicks like this were rampant.  Maybe the products have continued since then and I haven&#39;t paid attention, but the one thing I remember is how unsuccessful they always were.  The reward of playing outside, the motivation as well, is fun.  Good ol&#39; Sandlot kind of fun.  Watches aren&#39;t going to encourage this behavior... especially at a premium.  As a nerd, I think these watches are awesome, but as a parent I&#39;m like, &amp;quot;Really?&amp;quot;  Cool idea, but it ain&#39;t gonna happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yanko Design - Modern Industrial Design News&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yankodesign.com/2011/07/11/watch-encourages-play/&#34;&gt;Watch Encourages Play&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dreamworks, Pixar and storytelling</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/06/25/dreamworks-pixar-and-storytelling/</id>
    <updated>2011-06-26T00:51:13Z</updated>
    <published>2011-06-26T00:51:13Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;figure id=&#34;attachment_2844&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-2844&#34; style=&#34;width: 202px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34;&gt;[&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2844 &#34; title=&#34;megamind&#34; src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/megamind.jpg?w=202&amp;#038;resize=202%2C300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;202&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;figcaption id=&#34;caption-attachment-2844&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;I love this poster art in the movie. Hilarious!&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The family and I finally watched Megamind the other night.  I was really impressed. The story was creative and different, but I was mostly amazed with the facial expressions –  really sucked me into the story. Also, a few weeks ago, we watched How to Train Your Dragon for the first time.  That has to be my favorite Dreamworks film to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to thinking about Dreamworks and Pixar.  Dreamworks has intermittent success.  Kung Fu Panda was really good (I&#39;m excited to see the second one). Monsters versus Aliens was fun, but not great. Madagascar was one of the funniest movies they’ve made, but also not great. And by great, I guess I mean timeless.  Little Mermaid is still enjoyed by children today, like mine. It&#39;s timeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pixar, on the other hand… well, it&#39;s interesting to hear all the hype about Pixar&#39;s awesome-flick streak.  Well, I&#39;m kind of &amp;quot;eh&amp;quot; about Cars 2, right now - I&#39;d much rather see an Incredibles 2 right now but I digress. Pixar can tell a story and they create these beautiful works of art… their “timeless” success ratio is essentially pretty darn high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;It’s all about Storytelling.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pixar’s documentary mentions that it wasn’t computer animation that killed traditional animation, it was poor story telling.  The Princess and the Frog was a great way to prove this hypothesis. It wasn’t amazing, but it’s still up there for my family – very close to timeless.  (Who knew &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goliath_(Gargoyles)&#34;&gt;Goliath&lt;/a&gt; could sing!? Wow!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, who’s the better storyteller here?  Pixar has some really great original and successful stuff.  Dreamworks - well, How to Train Your Dragon was amazing, but it’s based off a book written by someone else.  Megamind was also amazing, but it’s just a twist on Superman.  Creative? Very. Timeless? Ehhhh… not sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Pixar isn’t perfect, they’re definitely the better story tellers.  But here’s the thing, though: Dreamworks is more fun oriented than Pixar is.  Pixar tells these beautiful stories of struggle and life changing resolutions.  Dreamworks is like, “Let’s blow crap up! Wooooo!”  Their story telling doesn’t feel as refined because they don’t want to be.  They just want to give people a good time at the movies. Nothing wrong with that, it just makes it harder to be “timeless.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Which is better? Ford or Chevy? Apple OSX or Microsoft Windows?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DreamWorks or Pixar?  Neither and both.  Ok, so DreamWorks hasn’t been as successful at the box office and has landed pretty close to bankruptcy a couple of times. But, remember, Apple and GM came pretty close to destruction as well.  (And yes, Apple fanboys/girls, Apple&#39;s stuff is awesome, but even Windows has its good points.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, sometimes you want that beautiful movie and sometimes you just want to watch stuff explode, you know?  Timelessness be damned.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Puss In Boots? Like, a prequel?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/06/25/puss-in-boots-like-a-prequel/</id>
    <updated>2011-06-25T18:05:15Z</updated>
    <published>2011-06-25T18:05:15Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hm. Looks pretty cool. I dunno about these spinoff prequels though...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;embed-youtube&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center; display: block;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&#39;youtube-player&#39; type=&#39;text/html&#39; width=&#39;580&#39; height=&#39;327&#39; src=&#39;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Znuq-daWfLE?version=3&amp;#038;rel=1&amp;#038;fs=1&amp;#038;autohide=2&amp;#038;showsearch=0&amp;#038;showinfo=1&amp;#038;iv_load_policy=1&amp;#038;wmode=transparent&#39; allowfullscreen=&#39;true&#39; style=&#39;border:0;&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>View of Endeavor’s launch</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/05/20/view-of-endeavors-launch/</id>
    <updated>2011-05-20T18:43:28Z</updated>
    <published>2011-05-20T18:43:28Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uproxx.com/news/2011/05/space-shuttle-endeavor-launches-on-its-final-mission/comment-page-1/#page/3&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/05/299726560.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uproxx.com/news/2011/05/space-shuttle-endeavor-launches-on-its-final-mission/comment-page-1/#page/3&#34;&gt;Photos And Video From Space Shuttle Endeavor’s Final Mission&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Warcraft 3, Oh yea.</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/05/09/warcraft-3-oh-yea/</id>
    <updated>2011-05-10T00:48:38Z</updated>
    <published>2011-05-10T00:48:38Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/05/screenclip.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/05/screenclip.jpg?w=300&amp;#038;resize=300%2C239&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;ScreenClip&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;239&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2822&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The CAT 5e diet.</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/04/20/the-cat-5e-diet/</id>
    <updated>2011-04-20T18:49:10Z</updated>
    <published>2011-04-20T18:49:10Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/20110420-034859.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/20110420-034859.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20110420-034859.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the Toad lunch...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/20110420-035841.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/20110420-035841.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20110420-035841.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Working for “internal” clients</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/04/14/working-for-internal-clients/</id>
    <updated>2011-04-15T03:02:50Z</updated>
    <published>2011-04-15T03:02:50Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;the-it-crowd&#34; style=&#34;border-right:0;border-top:0;display:block;float:none;margin-left:auto;border-left:0;margin-right:auto;border-bottom:0;&#34; height=&#34;236&#34; alt=&#34;the-it-crowd&#34; src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/theitcrowd.jpg?resize=420%2C236&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience with designing for profit comes mostly from “external” clients.  In my current position, though, I work with more “internal” clients. If you’re not familiar with the difference, in my example, I work &lt;strong&gt;with&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;for&lt;/strong&gt; the people requesting my services.  It’s a different dynamic, yes, but it doesn’t change the customer service aspect of the entire interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my current position, I deal a lot with different departments asking for updates, new pages, or just general consulting for their pages on the site.  When it comes to my relationship with them, I treat the situation as if it was a freelancer-client relationship - respectful and professional, but friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I’ve noticed others handling the same situation in the opposite manner.  It perplexes me when I see that – that type of situation blocks innovation, creativity, and beneficial relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interactions can be broken down into so many different elements. I’m going to focus on my biggest two, listening and speaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, and probably most important, never dismiss their thoughts and opinions.  It’s hard enough to think of new and exciting ideas by yourself, why would you block possible inspiration?  Hear them out to the end, tell them you’ll take it under consideration and then ACTUALLY consider their ideas.  Whether the ideas get used or not depends on the project, but one must always be open to outside influences lest become stale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, although these clients are considered coworkers, they still require your services.  Treating everyone with the same respect will go a long way professionally and personally.  Also, getting tasks done is easier and, dare I say, enjoyable when people are in friendlier moods. So, speak respectfully, regardless of how little they know about the service you offer.  Our job is to filter through their request and find the problems and solutions, that means understanding the client too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know customers/clients can be a pain and I’m not below making fun of some of the silly ones, or talking a little smack about the aggravating ones (not in public, ever.).  I still respect them - in the end it’s their requests that keeps me working.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Giggidy</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/04/07/giggidy/</id>
    <updated>2011-04-07T22:55:01Z</updated>
    <published>2011-04-07T22:55:01Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/20110407-075438.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/20110407-075438.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20110407-075438.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Coolest “Share this” method ever.</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/04/02/coolest-share-this-method-ever/</id>
    <updated>2011-04-02T18:05:52Z</updated>
    <published>2011-04-02T18:05:52Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a href=&#34;http://cortexapp.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-2799&#34; title=&#34;Cortex&#34; src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/cortex.png?w=300&amp;#038;resize=300%2C185&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;185&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Cortex]&lt;a href=&#34;http://cortexapp.com/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; for Google Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two thoughts on this really cool sharing method. First, it&#39;s pretty, intuitive and fun. Yea, it&#39;s actually so cool, it&#39;s fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, where&#39;s the JQuery plugin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as using it, it does need more services. Right now it&#39;s only Facebook, Twitter, Tumblr, and Instapaper. Half of those I don&#39;t use.  Still, it&#39;s very very cool. &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/decglnkhpfoocpafihfbeodhgofefaoc?hl=en-US#&#34;&gt;Download it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I do not think it means what you think it means.</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/03/26/i-do-not-think-it-means-what-you-think-it-means/</id>
    <updated>2011-03-26T12:40:43Z</updated>
    <published>2011-03-26T12:40:43Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Am I reading this wrong or is their definition of &amp;quot;loyalty&amp;quot; a little skewed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/20110326-083834.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/20110326-083834.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20110326-083834.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Updated wallpaper</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/03/21/updated-wallpaper/</id>
    <updated>2011-03-21T20:34:09Z</updated>
    <published>2011-03-21T20:34:09Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Rammy says &#39;Get back to work.&#39;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/20110321-053248.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/20110321-053248.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20110321-053248.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mouse surfing</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/03/21/mouse-surfing/</id>
    <updated>2011-03-21T15:17:46Z</updated>
    <published>2011-03-21T15:17:46Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/20110321-121726.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/20110321-121726.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20110321-121726.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On Blockbuster</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/03/20/on-blockbuster/</id>
    <updated>2011-03-20T16:49:18Z</updated>
    <published>2011-03-20T16:49:18Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I rented my first movie from a Blockbuster Kiosk the other day and I started thinking about Blockbuster&#39;s survival. It doesn&#39;t look very good. It&#39;s three generations behind, for crying out loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the early years of the milennia, I said to my dad that Netflix will never replace the in-store experience. Although the in store experience is now a kiosk at every drug store, gas station, grocery store, and truck stop, I&#39;m still sort of correct. Yet, Blockbuster continued to maintain it&#39;s storefronts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://dealbook.nytimes.com/2011/02/24/blockbusters-fall-and-netflixs-rise-in-pictures/?ref=blockbusterinc&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2787&#34; title=&#34;Blockbuster&#39;s Fall and Netflix&#39;s Rise, in Pictures - NYTimes.com&#34; src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/blockbusters-fall-and-netflixs-rise-in-pictures-nytimes-com.png?w=300&amp;#038;resize=300%2C155&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;155&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image is from this &lt;a href=&#34;http://dealbook.nytimes.com/2011/02/24/blockbusters-fall-and-netflixs-rise-in-pictures/?ref=blockbusterinc&#34;&gt;article on the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;. Good illustration on Blockbuster&#39;s fall.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix took off with it&#39;s mail DVD service back in the day. Blockbuster should have jumped on that QUICK. But, instead, they waited until Netflix had a beachhead. Worse off, they passed up a chance to &lt;strong&gt;buy Netflix out&lt;/strong&gt;. It seems like Blockbuster did the same thing with the kiosk. Redbox owns the market there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steaming? I didn&#39;t even know Blockbuster had streaming. But so what, I&#39;ll be able to rent videos on Facebook soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&#39;re just not relevant anymore. They stopped innovating and they&#39;re being retired because of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last time I was at a Blockbuster was about 6 months ago to rent a game that my brother and I could play together. It seemed busy enough, but not nearly as busy as it did six years ago when I last visited a Blockbuster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&#39;t matter now, but I wonder what will become of the brand. I remember back when I was a kid, employees &lt;strong&gt;knew their stuff&lt;/strong&gt;.  They knew movies and could recommend a good one at the drop of a hat. That culture seems to have waned in an attempt to save money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they still can, they need to go back to the movie-geek mentality and embrace it.  That is the only worthy asset they have left and it&#39;s something the online video market can&#39;t reproduce well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close all the storefronts.  Open up in-store indpendant kiosks, a &amp;quot;genius bar&amp;quot; if you will, for movies.  An actual person to talk to about movies at Best Buys, Targets, Walmarts, etc.  Blockbuster will pretty much run that store&#39;s movie section.  Plus they still manage the unmanned kiosks (which aren&#39;t bad really, but where&#39;s the mobile app?!).  As for streaming, Blockbuster should get with Facebook and partner up for the right to display ALL the movie content on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are too many iconic businesses closing down these days.  I hate to see you go, Blockbuster, but it&#39;s your own fault.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What does that slider do!?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/03/17/what-does-that-slider-do/</id>
    <updated>2011-03-18T00:32:53Z</updated>
    <published>2011-03-18T00:32:53Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seriously, is it volume? It&#39;s in the Settings app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/20110317-083154.jpg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/20110317-083154.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;20110317-083154.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Just need a talking dog…</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/03/17/just-need-a-talking-dog/</id>
    <updated>2011-03-17T19:27:01Z</updated>
    <published>2011-03-17T19:27:01Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/dornob/~3/r8q16fAh1Xc/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/real-movie-up-home.jpg?w=580&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am showing this to my kids first thing when I get home! Cool! Follow the link, there&#39;s more pics and video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via Dornob  &lt;a href=&#34;http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/dornob/~3/r8q16fAh1Xc/&#34;&gt;300 Helium Balloons Float Real ‘Up’ House 10,000 Feet High&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Happy Birthday Zelda!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/03/13/happy-birthday-zelda/</id>
    <updated>2011-03-14T00:14:07Z</updated>
    <published>2011-03-14T00:14:07Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m sure everyone has seen &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pixiv.net/member_illust.php?mode=medium&amp;amp;illust_id=16868303&#34; title=&#34;Zelda Painting&#34;&gt;this poster&lt;/a&gt; already, well I just ran across the making of video. Wow. I wish I could draw/paint.  Also, I wish I could have that painting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;embed-youtube&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center; display: block;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&#39;youtube-player&#39; type=&#39;text/html&#39; width=&#39;580&#39; height=&#39;327&#39; src=&#39;https://www.youtube.com/embed/r1mhfHklIRQ?version=3&amp;#038;rel=1&amp;#038;fs=1&amp;#038;autohide=2&amp;#038;showsearch=0&amp;#038;showinfo=1&amp;#038;iv_load_policy=1&amp;#038;wmode=transparent&#39; allowfullscreen=&#39;true&#39; style=&#39;border:0;&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I love slides.</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/03/10/i-love-slides/</id>
    <updated>2011-03-10T17:24:02Z</updated>
    <published>2011-03-10T17:24:02Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://notes.analogdialog.com/post/3745201382&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/tumblr_lhswznoyvx1qf0xk3o1_500.jpg?w=580&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ANALOG|DIALOG&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://notes.analogdialog.com/post/3745201382&#34;&gt;Turett Collaborative Architects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Best. Kids. Room. Ever.</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/03/06/best-kids-room-ever/</id>
    <updated>2011-03-06T23:25:01Z</updated>
    <published>2011-03-06T23:25:01Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mymodernmet.com/profiles/blogs/ultimate-pirate-ship-bedroom&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/pirateshipbedroom3.jpg?w=580&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy cow, this is one of the coolest designs I&#39;ve ever seen! Brilliantly executed, it has so many kid friendly features (read: kid at heart).  I love it. Wow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mymodernmet.com/profiles/blogs/ultimate-pirate-ship-bedroom&#34;&gt;Ultimate Pirate Ship Bedroom (14 pics) - My Modern Metropolis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dudecraft.com/2011/03/pirate-bedroom.html&#34;&gt;Dudecraft.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ikea hack: Slide projector, perhaps more?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Juan Orozco</name>
      <uri>https://juanorozco.com/</uri>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.juanorozco.com/2011/03/06/ikea-hack-slide-projector-perhaps-more/</id>
    <updated>2011-03-06T22:16:12Z</updated>
    <published>2011-03-06T22:16:12Z</published>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Ikeahacker/~3/YCWLTvD_fB8/diy-slide-projector.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/fmcgmg7gkayxwzn.jpg?w=580&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m thinking combine this with a small LCD screen, maybe from a hacked older generation iPod?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via ikea hacker &lt;a href=&#34;http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Ikeahacker/~3/YCWLTvD_fB8/diy-slide-projector.html&#34;&gt;DIY Slide Projector&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
