<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Audio on Juan Orozco</title>
    <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/tags/audio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Audio on Juan Orozco</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 01:54:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.juanorozco.com/tags/audio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What a failing hard drive sounds like.</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2010/08/25/what-a-failing-hard-drive-sounds-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 01:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2010/08/25/what-a-failing-hard-drive-sounds-like/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m emptying a USB drive as I type this so I can back up the bad drive. I thought it would be fun to post the nasty sound it was making in the mean time.  This is the first hard drive to ever fail on me - it&#39;s also not one of the oldest HD&#39;s I have either. Scary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zune Software: FAIL.</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2008/09/27/zune-software-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 21:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2008/09/27/zune-software-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I bought my Zune, it was &lt;a href=&#34;http://guamaso.com/2008/07/06/the-precious-80-gig-zune&#34;&gt;after careful research and investigation&lt;/a&gt; that I decided to purchase one.   I knew it was a device with huge dreams of being the number one portable media player.   I knew that the path to that dream was long and dangerous.   But I bought one anyway.   I did it because I thought it had the potential and the drive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Precious: 80 Gig Zune</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2008/07/06/the-precious-80-gig-zune/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2008/07/06/the-precious-80-gig-zune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Forgot to mention that with the great idea good ol&#39; George (W. Bush) concocted to stimulate the economy, I was able to finally purchase myself a PMD (portable media device). It took me a while to figure out which one I wanted the most. I started looking at what was out there and I know that I wanted a large hard drive to store all my music rather then loading just a small portion of it.   I have about 30 gigs of music as it is so I wanted at least a 40 gig drive, but I would prefer 60 to 80.   Of all the features, the hard drive is all I really cared about.   I would be happy with a small black and white screen and a huge hard drive.   But since they don&#39;t make anything like that I was stuck trying to figure out the best player for the money.   It came down to the IPod and the Zune.   I really liked the Creative Labs Zen, but it was too expensive and the hard drive was too small.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sennheisers freaking rock…</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2008/06/24/sennheisers-freaking-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2008 13:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2008/06/24/sennheisers-freaking-rock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-461&#34; title=&#34;hd280&#34; src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/guamaso.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/06/hd280-300x300.jpg?resize=300%2C300&#34; alt=&#34;Sennheiser HD 280&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;I love audio stuff: It&#39;s my vice.   I can&#39;t really afford the stuff I really want (Klipsch Reference Series... our love was not meant to be...), but I can still get stuff that sounds great.   Ciriana got me a Klipsch Synergy series subwoofer, and it&#39;s been a lot of fun.   I bought some Yamaha speakers at the BX in Germany when I moved out there, and I think they are very close to the rest of the Klipsch Synergy series.   Right now I still have old Sony speakers for the fronts and center...   and they will remain in their current service until I all my other projects are done... sigh.   One thing I definitely think I will not compromise on are headphones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
