<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on Juan Orozco</title>
    <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on Juan Orozco</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 01:58:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.juanorozco.com/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Over the Rainbow</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2010/09/12/over-the-rainbow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 01:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2010/09/12/over-the-rainbow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cover art is a little odd, but the music is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2010/09/p_480_320_a5435de3-033d-4ef9-b954-6d0a694b66f7.jpeg?w=580&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2010/09/p_480_320_a5435de3-033d-4ef9-b954-6d0a694b66f7.jpeg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinball Wizard on a Uke</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2010/08/23/pinball-wizard-on-a-uke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 15:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2010/08/23/pinball-wizard-on-a-uke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Awesome.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--YouTube Error: bad URL entered--&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;via Dude Craft  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dudecraft.com/2010/07/duo-does-pinball-wizard.html&#34;&gt;DUO does Pinball Wizard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Radio Ball Device</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2010/07/02/radio-ball-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2010 04:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2010/07/02/radio-ball-device/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yankodesign.com/2010/05/12/more-radio-rolling-more-gaga/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;https://i0.wp.com/iam.juano.info/files/2010/07/radioball05.jpg?w=580&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I love workspaces. I like finding new configurations and new items for my desk or work area.  The Radio Ball is such a brilliant idea that can be used for many different purposes.  Games, discovery, and more.  The one I am focused on is desk radio.  It&#39;s the not so glamorous desk ornament turned hip and cool.  Just rotate until you find your station then rotate along the new axis to control volume (at least that&#39;s what I gathered from the video).  Love it.  Perhaps a digital (mp3 player) version in the future?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zune Software: FAIL.</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2008/09/27/zune-software-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 21:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2008/09/27/zune-software-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I bought my Zune, it was &lt;a href=&#34;http://guamaso.com/2008/07/06/the-precious-80-gig-zune&#34;&gt;after careful research and investigation&lt;/a&gt; that I decided to purchase one.   I knew it was a device with huge dreams of being the number one portable media player.   I knew that the path to that dream was long and dangerous.   But I bought one anyway.   I did it because I thought it had the potential and the drive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On a Final Fantasy Kick, there should be a group…</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2008/07/16/on-a-final-fantasy-kick-there-should-be-a-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 13:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2008/07/16/on-a-final-fantasy-kick-there-should-be-a-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know why I have been jonesin&#39; for some Final Fantasy.   I went searching my cd cases for all of my Final Fantasy music that I backed up to data CD&#39;s just in case (I lost all my mp3&#39;s some time ago, good thinking on my part! Yay!).   I uploaded them all to &lt;a href=&#34;http://guamaso.com/2008/07/06/the-precious-80-gig-zune&#34;&gt;the Precious&lt;/a&gt; the other day and I have been listening non stop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Precious: 80 Gig Zune</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2008/07/06/the-precious-80-gig-zune/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2008/07/06/the-precious-80-gig-zune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Forgot to mention that with the great idea good ol&#39; George (W. Bush) concocted to stimulate the economy, I was able to finally purchase myself a PMD (portable media device). It took me a while to figure out which one I wanted the most. I started looking at what was out there and I know that I wanted a large hard drive to store all my music rather then loading just a small portion of it.   I have about 30 gigs of music as it is so I wanted at least a 40 gig drive, but I would prefer 60 to 80.   Of all the features, the hard drive is all I really cared about.   I would be happy with a small black and white screen and a huge hard drive.   But since they don&#39;t make anything like that I was stuck trying to figure out the best player for the money.   It came down to the IPod and the Zune.   I really liked the Creative Labs Zen, but it was too expensive and the hard drive was too small.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finally Bought new Linkin Park CD</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2008/02/10/finally-bought-new-linkin-park-cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 02:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2008/02/10/finally-bought-new-linkin-park-cd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ciriana says that I turned her on to Linkin Park on our first date. At first I didn&#39;t really like them until I listened to the lyrics. My problem with music is that all I can hear is the melody; I can never distinguish the words. I liked the musical parts of their songs, but the words I did hear kind of kept me at a distance. When I finally focused my attention on what they were saying I enjoyed the music more. It also taught me a very important life lesson, as corny as this sounds: never pass judgment until you have all the information. I said to others that they were a stupid band and that it&#39;s not music, but when I actually listened, I realized that I had assumed that their &amp;quot;sound&amp;quot; was destructive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
