<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Juan Orozco</title>
    <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Juan Orozco</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 01:01:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.juanorozco.com/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tactus Technology Can Make Physical Buttons Rise Up Out of Touchscreens – Core77</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/blog/2012/tactus-technology-can-make-physical-buttons-rise-up-out-of-touchscreens-core77/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 01:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/blog/2012/tactus-technology-can-make-physical-buttons-rise-up-out-of-touchscreens-core77/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.core77.com/blog/ux/tactus_technology_can_make_physical_buttons_rise_up_out_of_touchscreens_23029.asp&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;http://juanthedesigner.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0tactus02.jpg?w=580&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The possibilities of this are astounding.  Obviously some sort of braille reader.  It&#39;s not very dynamic (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tactustechnology.com/technology.html&#34;&gt;it can only have one set of buttons at a time, apparently&lt;/a&gt;) but just from a quick conversation, I&#39;m thinking Apple could use this to completely remove all the buttons on the iphone. For example, the volume buttons don&#39;t do anything in certain situations. With this technology, the buttons would be gone in these situations!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Precious: 80 Gig Zune</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/blog/2008/the-precious-80-gig-zune/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 13:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/blog/2008/the-precious-80-gig-zune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Forgot to mention that with the great idea good ol&#39; George (W. Bush) concocted to stimulate the economy, I was able to finally purchase myself a PMD (portable media device). It took me a while to figure out which one I wanted the most. I started looking at what was out there and I know that I wanted a large hard drive to store all my music rather then loading just a small portion of it.   I have about 30 gigs of music as it is so I wanted at least a 40 gig drive, but I would prefer 60 to 80.   Of all the features, the hard drive is all I really cared about.   I would be happy with a small black and white screen and a huge hard drive.   But since they don&#39;t make anything like that I was stuck trying to figure out the best player for the money.   It came down to the IPod and the Zune.   I really liked the Creative Labs Zen, but it was too expensive and the hard drive was too small.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sennheisers freaking rock…</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/blog/2008/sennheisers-freaking-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2008 13:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/blog/2008/sennheisers-freaking-rock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-461&#34; title=&#34;hd280&#34; src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/guamaso.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/06/hd280-300x300.jpg?resize=300%2C300&#34; alt=&#34;Sennheiser HD 280&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;I love audio stuff: It&#39;s my vice.   I can&#39;t really afford the stuff I really want (Klipsch Reference Series... our love was not meant to be...), but I can still get stuff that sounds great.   Ciriana got me a Klipsch Synergy series subwoofer, and it&#39;s been a lot of fun.   I bought some Yamaha speakers at the BX in Germany when I moved out there, and I think they are very close to the rest of the Klipsch Synergy series.   Right now I still have old Sony speakers for the fronts and center...   and they will remain in their current service until I all my other projects are done... sigh.   One thing I definitely think I will not compromise on are headphones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
