<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Juan Orozco</title>
    <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Juan Orozco</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 18:53:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.juanorozco.com/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chess problems</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/blog/2011/chess-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 18:53:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/blog/2011/chess-problems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My coworkers turned out to be some tough chess opponents so I downloaded a ton of old public domain books. The best part is how these books still contain relevant and interesting strategies for chess. Some were written in the late 1800&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ma’ Birthday’s Comin’</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/blog/2009/ma-birthdays-comin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 14:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/blog/2009/ma-birthdays-comin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s wishlist time. Last year was a pretty successful year for my annual personal holiday, I got Mario Kart, my sub-woofer, and a few other doo-dads. This year is a tough one for many people including my family and friends. I never expect gifts from them but they always ask what I want. It&#39;s also fun to just list the things I am excited about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Color Theory for Web Design and more.</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/blog/2008/color-theory-for-web-design-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 00:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/blog/2008/color-theory-for-web-design-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, a few years back, when I first started designing web sites, I designed sites on what I thought looked good. After they were built, I realized that they looked like crap. They layout, the color, the content, and the usability. As I progressed, I learned more and more even though I didn&#39;t completely know or understand the theories and practices behind web design. Now, as my designs&#39; quality increase, I feel like in order to really fine tune everything, I need to know and understand every aspect of every theory involving design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
