<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on Juan Orozco</title>
    <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/categories/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on Juan Orozco</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 22:05:41 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.juanorozco.com/categories/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>72 Hours of Fear</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/blog/2023/72-hours-of-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 22:05:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/blog/2023/72-hours-of-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This evening, I stared a bit longer in the mirror; at my hairline. I think my hair visibly thinned over the weekend. My hairline isn&#39;t something I fret over; it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; moving, but I can&#39;t do anything about it. I&#39;m trying to be more of a Stoicist in my 40s; I&#39;m trying to be more, you know, &amp;quot;WWMAD&amp;quot;? I&#39;m starting to wonder if the last few years would try even Marcus Aurelius&#39; dedication to calm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notebooks</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2020/01/23/notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 22:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2020/01/23/notebooks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Field Notes make some &lt;strong&gt;amazing&lt;/strong&gt; notebooks. My favorite, to this day, is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://fieldnotesbrand.com/products/shelterwood&#34;&gt;Shelterwood&lt;/a&gt; from the Field Notes quarterly subscription. A pocket sized notebook wrapped in a super thin vineer of cherry wood - just beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, they&#39;re just &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; small for planning and daily use - at least for me. To try to understand why, I experiemented with the opposite side of the spectrum. I started using an extra large size Moleskine cahier to see what my experience was with more real estate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Releasing Often</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/07/31/releasing-often/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 03:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/07/31/releasing-often/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of months back, my wife was working on updating our fence. Specifically, she was improving the gates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We had two gates. On the west side of the house, we had a small gate – mostly for people but wide enough for a mower. On the east side, we had a more massive vehicle entry. When we first built the fence about ten years ago, we had no idea what we were doing. We worked with what we had, and, in the end, we built a solid, working fence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is introspection</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/03/08/what-is-introspection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 04:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/03/08/what-is-introspection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you learn from mistakes? How do you see challenges? How do you take critique?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been wondering and theorizing about my own ability to self-analyze. I assume most people feel the same way towards self and others, that we all want success and happiness. Whatever that means to you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Movie Reviews – Annihilation and Automata</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/02/27/quick-movie-reviews-annihilation-and-automata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 03:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/02/27/quick-movie-reviews-annihilation-and-automata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been a HUGE Natalie Portman fan since &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110413/&#34;&gt;Leon&lt;/a&gt; (and a MEGA Gary Oldman fan for equally as long). I don&#39;t really have a problem with the Star Wars prequels but her participation in the Thor movies was totally punching below her weight. Still, if she had fun that&#39;s all that matters. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mars_Attacks!&#34;&gt;Mars Attacks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/V_for_Vendetta_%28film%29&#34;&gt;V for Vandetta&lt;/a&gt; are more of my favorites. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Swan_%28film%29&#34;&gt;Black Swan&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Other_Boleyn_Girl_%282008_film%29&#34;&gt;The Other Boleyn Girl&lt;/a&gt;, great performances of hers but not really my thing as far as movies go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burn Out</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/02/08/burn-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 12:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2019/02/08/burn-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started watching &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1YzwjfwNeEg&#34;&gt;Casey Neistat&#39;s latest video about YouTubers experiencing burn out&lt;/a&gt;. I eye-rolled at the title but I respect &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jG7dSXcfVqE&#34;&gt;Casey&#39;s views on life&lt;/a&gt;, so I watched it. It took me two sittings because in the beginning he seemed to over-empathize with his peers and I quickly lost interest with the story he told.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
