<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal on Juan Orozco</title>
    <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/tags/journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal on Juan Orozco</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 16:34:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.juanorozco.com/tags/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Veterans Day</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2018/11/11/veterans-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 16:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2018/11/11/veterans-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember taking the ASVAB in high school and recruiters calling me afterwards to join code breakers... apparently I showed aptitude for patterns. Goooo super ADD powers! 😂&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A short time later, the curiosity got to me and I went to the Marine recruiting place with questions. They showed me a video of boot camp. I thanked them for their time and never looked back. (I mean, it&#39;s called the crucible!) I learned from that video, though, to have great respect for people who CAN do those things and I defended their honor to naysayers whenever I could.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Builds: Cat Condo and Laptop Stand</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2017/12/11/builds-cat-condo-and-laptop-stand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2017/12/11/builds-cat-condo-and-laptop-stand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year we purchased a Ryobi cordless tool set and a Ryobi table saw. Nothing fancy but impressive upgrades from what we had... which wasn&#39;t much!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cat-condo-project-catcondoproject&#34;&gt;Cat Condo Project {#catcondoproject}&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past, we&#39;ve made the cats insulated homes from plastic totes. But they get nasty and nobody cleans them up so they eventually get tossed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Four Way Test</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2017/01/29/the-four-way-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 05:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2017/01/29/the-four-way-test/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I have struggled with the America &amp;quot;I remember&amp;quot; versus the America &amp;quot;I see before me&amp;quot;. I am aware that there is a bias at work that paints my past as rosier than it really is. Still, when I run into words like these, I wonder where we stumbled:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Po the Pathfinder: origins</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2016/05/30/po-the-pathfinder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 02:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2016/05/30/po-the-pathfinder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.creativeandflow.com/images/2016/03/po-the-pathfinder.large.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/m.creativeandflow.com/images/2016/03/po-the-pathfinder.medium.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Po the Pathfinder&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I owned a VW Golf while we lived in Germany. I loved that car. It was simple. No crazy gadgets. No power steering. No air conditioning. No fuel injection. No power brakes. &lt;strong&gt;Just car.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I loved that car, alas, it didn&#39;t make sense to bring it back to the states with us. Unfortunately, people rarely buy those old cars so we had to junk it. My heart broke into a million pieces that day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I heart pens</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2016/05/28/i-heart-pens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 04:17:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2016/05/28/i-heart-pens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.creativeandflow.com/images/2016/03/pens.small.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;http://m.creativeandflow.com/images/2016/03/pens.large.jpg&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I have an emergent idea or thought that I need to record, I usually do it on paper. I have a subscription to Evernote, Dropbox, Google Drive. I even keep a private Github repo available for simple text notes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind dump: The last few months</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/10/29/mind-dump-the-last-few-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 03:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/10/29/mind-dump-the-last-few-months/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s interesting how life just happens. It cliché but it&#39;s true. One moment your having a margarita, the next minute you find out your little family is about to be a lot less little.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I mostly just want to mind dump some thoughts and maybe I&#39;ll elaborate on them later and maybe I won&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build your own thing</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/07/04/build-your-own-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2015 20:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/07/04/build-your-own-thing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/m.juanorozco.com/photos/2015/07/crv-engine.large.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;CR-V Engine&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s publishings out there saying we live in a throw-away-I-want-it-now culture. &lt;strong&gt;They&#39;re probably right.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I fall into that pit from time to time. I&#39;ve been known to go to the store for something I need simply because I&#39;d rather not wait the week for free shipping to delivery my item.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrossFit: Day One</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/04/07/crossfit-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 17:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/04/07/crossfit-day-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/res.cloudinary.com/depnutmkm/image/upload/c_scale,w_800/v1428373890/P1010080_jr56rq.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Jelly Fish&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don’t like gyms, but I never knew why until today. Today was my first day doing CrossFit. Let me first get my thoughts out on CrossFit before I explain my discovery.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;crossfit-is-bad-ass-crossfitisbadass&#34;&gt;CrossFit is bad ass {#crossfitisbadass}&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the trainer we had. She was amazing. She was empathetic yet assertive; firm yet encouraging.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iterations of life</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/02/16/iterations-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 03:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2015/02/16/iterations-of-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.creativeandflow.com/images/2015/02/wright.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/m.creativeandflow.com/images/2015/02/wright_sm.jpg?w=580&#34; alt=&#34;Wright Memorial - Kitty Hawk, NC&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m infatuated with the concept of iteration. As a creator of web things, I am no stranger to the concept. But as a member of society, father, husband, friend, and more; I&#39;ve noticed more and more useful applications for iteration in all aspects of life outside of work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attempt the… FRENCH MACARON</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2014/07/26/attempt-the-french-macaron/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 05:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2014/07/26/attempt-the-french-macaron/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Baking is the closest I will probably ever get to a laboratory science and I am ok with that. I love the sciences and I like laboratory science but can you eat HCl and live? Unless you have Wolverine&#39;s healing factor, I highly doubt it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thought: Intense focus</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2014/07/21/thought-intense-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 02:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2014/07/21/thought-intense-focus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It takes years to develop and refine a skill. It takes longer still to fix a character flaw or improve a virtue. People have proven that, with proper focus, you can turn your life around. The goal is not to change but to build discipline or values that didn&#39;t exist, or barely existed, before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home Automata</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2014/06/05/home-automata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2014/06/05/home-automata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The idea of walking from one room to another, talking to your family over the phone, but not tied to a device in any way. The caller&#39;s voice travels with you to each room through speakers built into the wall. Presence sensors in each room detect your movement between rooms. A sensitive microphone also embedded in each room, but processed and cleaned up by a fancy computer somewhere in the house (so your voice doesn&#39;t sound &amp;quot;far away&amp;quot;.)... &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; is the future I remember being told was in store for us. Un-tethered and automated; &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online Web Apps for private journaling.</title>
      <link>https://www.juanorozco.com/2009/06/10/online-web-apps-for-private-journalling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 03:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.juanorozco.com/2009/06/10/online-web-apps-for-private-journalling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve started up my personal journal again.  (Yes, I am writing a diary...)  Only this time, I thought I&#39;d try a virtual journal in the hopes that I would continue writing in it longer than a few months.  I enjoy writing and chronicling my thoughts, but writing in a book never worked out for me.  I would jot down my thoughts and ideas more often if I could write from anywhere and anytime.  What better way to write on the go than with my iPhone?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
